本双语字幕来源于网络  仅供学习交流
Anthy
一想到我老婆
When I think of my wife...
我总是想到她的头颅
...I always think of her head.
我会想像怎么剖开她可爱的头骨
I picture cracking her lovely skull...
细细折解她的脑袋
unspooling her brains...
好让我找到答案
trying to get answers.
我想问婚姻里那些最基本的问题
The primal questions of any marriage.
“你在想什么？”
"What are you thinking?"
“你感觉如何？”
"How are you feeling?"
“我们对彼此做了什么？”
"What have we done to each other?"
控制
“7月5日  事发上午”
“酒吧”
爱尔兰王子大驾光临了
The Irish prince graces us with his presence.
王子殿下不想被弄湿
His majesty prefers not to be moistened.
我带了礼物给你
I got you a present.
我讨厌这游戏  - 你以前很喜欢
Oh. I hated this game. You loved it.
是你以前很喜欢
You loved it.
谢谢，我会加进我的收藏里
Thank you. I'll add it to the collection.
帮我倒一杯波本酒吧
Can you pour me a bourbon?
怎么了，小神经质？
What's up, Jitters?
如果你不说，那么我只好再自爆
Well, if you're not going to talk I'm gonna have to...
玛戈邓恩的另一个悲惨故事
fill the silence with another excruciating story by Margo Dunne.
我可以告诉你我最近的客服经验
I could tell you about my recent customer service experience...
我要更换网路业者  - 我喜欢这一个
changing Internet service providers. I like that one.
或我看见长得跟莫妮卡一样的人那次
Or how about the time I saw that woman who looked exactly like my friend Monica?
但她不是莫妮卡，是陌生人
But it wasn't Monica. It was a total stranger.
但她也叫做莫妮卡
Who was also named Monica.
真的很有趣  - 不错
Made it kind of interesting. It's great.
我今天不太好
I'm just having a bad day.
因为爱咪？  - 今天是我们结婚纪念日
Amy? It's our anniversary.
五周年  - 五年了？
Five years. Five?
真是快啊
That came fast.
而且风风雨雨
And furious.
我快乐得要疯了，像个傻子
I'm so crazy, stupid happy.
“2005年1月8日”
我认识了一个男孩子
I met a boy.
一个超棒、可爱、又酷的大帅哥
A great, sweet, gorgeous, cool-ass guy.
不好意思，小姐
Excuse me, miss?
我只是想提醒你
I just want you to be careful...
别把那瓶修士酿的比利时白啤酒乱放
where you put down that monk-brewed Belgian wheat beer...
这里只剩三罐超淡啤酒和一瓶水果酒
because the party's down to three Beast Lights and a bottle of Pucker.
那我这瓶可能会引人犯罪
It might attract some desperate characters.
有可能
It could.
毕竟这些阿米希派可是来享乐的
I mean, the Amish are on a Rumspringa.
他们已经帮我吃光一盘肉肴小点
They already relieved me of my artisanal meat platter.
终于有人念好这个字了
Finally, someone tells me how to pronounce that word.
你说“肉”？
"Meat"?
对，是ㄖ不是ㄌ
Yes, "meat." One syllable.
谢谢，我要喝的是谁的啤酒？
Thank you. Whose beer am I about to drink?
别告诉我
Don't tell me.
我来猜，谁是你的菜？
Let's see, who's your type?
我觉得你不是那种安安静静
I don't see you sitting quietly...
听对方大谈普鲁斯特主题论文的女生
while he bloviates on his postgrad thesis about Proust.
不会吧，是他？
Uh-oh. Is that him?
爱挖苦人，自我中心，玩笑开不停
Ironic hipster, so self-aware,he makes everything a joke.
我喜欢有幽默感，不刻意说笑的人
I prefer men who are funny, not "funny."
你又是哪一型？
What type are you?
美国价值表率的纯朴密苏里男儿
Corn-fed, salt-of-the-earth Missouri guy.
密苏里？
Missouri? Mmm-hmm.
真可爱
Cute. Hmm.
纽约人？  - 我的世界只到哈德逊河为止
Native New Yorker?  The world ends at the Hudson.
你叫什么名字？
What's your name?
爱咪
Amy.
爱咪，你是谁？
Well, Amy, who are you?
A：我是得奖的手工艺师
A, I'm an award-winning scrimshander.
B：我是小有影响力的军阀
B, I'm a moderately influential warlord. Hmm.
C：我帮杂志撰写人格测验
C, I write personality quizzes for magazines.
你的手太细嫩不可能做手工艺
Okay. Your hands are far too delicate for real scrimshaw work...
我刚好在“中级军阀周刊”负责颁发证书
and I happen to be a charter subscriber to Middling Warlord Weekly...
所以我应该认得你
so I'd recognize you.
所以我选C
I'm gonna go with
你呢？
And you?
你又是谁？
Who are you?
我是拯救你离开这个“精彩”派对的人
I'm the guy to save you from all this awesomeness.
所以你帮男性杂志写文章
Oh, so, you write for a men's magazine.
老天，这样你不就是男人专家了吗？
God, does that make you an expert on being a man?
不
No.
我写的是穿着、品酒之类的
It's what to wear, what to drink.
还有怎么鬼扯
How to bullshit.
我绝不会对你鬼扯
Never with you.
最好是
Ha, ha. No
我说真的
I mean it.
我很难相信你
It's hard to believe you. Why?
为什么？
Why?
应该是因为你的下巴
I think it's your chin.
我的下巴？
My chin?
对，看起来像坏人
Yeah, it's quite villainous.
那这样呢？
Okay, how's this?
百分之百老实，不鬼扯
A hundred percent true, no bullshit.
好吧
Okay-
我们都搬到纽约
We all move to New York...
最后住在这种小鸟笼里，还不只如此
and we end up living in these little cubby holes, and that's not it.
到外面来，这才是活在纽约
Come outside. Then, you're in it.
你得看看这个
You have to see this.
你好
Hey-
我现在一定要亲你
I have to kiss you now.
是吗？
Is that right?
我不能放你走过这片糖风暴却不亲你
I can't let you go through a sugar storm unkissed. Hmm.
等等
Oh. Wait a second.
这样才对
There you go.
尼克邓恩
Nick Dunne...
我真的喜欢你
I really like you.
所以这次结婚周年纪念
So, is Amy gonna do one of those anniversary...
爱咪也要玩寻宝游戏？
treasure hunts?
你是说专门设计来证明她老公
You mean the forced march designed to prove...
是个健忘没心肝的混蛋的游戏？
what an oblivious and uncaring asshole her husband is?
哇
Wow.
我都不知道人生是为了什么
Life. I don't remember the point.
游戏公司可是用心良苦呢
Deep Hasbro thoughts.
该你转
Spin.
去年让她大抓狂的是哪个线索？
What was the clue last year she got so mad about?
“你可怜的爱咪一感冒
"When your poor Amy has a cold...
餐馆马上推出这一道”
"this dessert just must be sold."
答案是什么？
The answer?
我到现在还不知道，小戈
I still don't know the answer, Go.
几年前你都知道  - 几年前还很有趣
A few years ago, you'd have known.
第一年是纸婚，送纸礼物
A few years ago, it was fun.Year one, the traditional gift was paper.
她买了精美的笔记本让我写小说
She got me a beautiful notebook.Told me to go write my novel.
你送她什么？
What did you get her?
一个风筝
A kite. Hmm.
她从没放过风筝  - 好吧
She'd never flown a kite. Okay.
总之呢，第四年要送花
Anyway. Year four, flowers.
她带我到后院看枯萎的玫瑰花丛
She led me outside to the dying rosebush in the backyard.
真有象征性
Ugh, that's symbolic.
是啊
Yeah.
五周年是什么婚？
What's the gift for five?
木婚
Wood.
那你买了什么？  - 没有好礼物是木头的
So, what did you get her?  There's no good gift for wood.
你回家用力干她，用老二甩她
I know! Go home, fuck her brains out, slap her with your penis.
呛她，“这可是块好木头，贱人”
"There's some wood for you, bitch."
这里是酒吧
The Bar.
当然，你等等
Why, yes. Hang on one second.
是爱管闲事的瓦力
Hey, it's Watchful Wally.
瓦力，什么事？
Hey, Walt. What's going on?
谢谢，我很快就回去，没问题，再见
Oh.Thanks very much. I'll be right there. All right, bye-bye.
兄弟，你在外面干嘛？
Hey, buddy. What are you doing out here?
谢啦，瓦力
Thanks, Walt!
爱咪？
Ame?
爱咪
Amy!
“北卡塞基警局”
有人吗？
Hello?
进来吧
Come on in.
你们好
Hey-
邓恩先生  - 你好
Mister Dunne. Hi.
隆妲邦妮警探，这位是吉姆吉尔宾
I'm Detective Rhonda Boney. This is Officer James Gilpin.
我们了解您妻子可能有危险
We understand there are concerns about your wife.
我不知道我老婆在哪，一回家就这样
I don't know where my wife is.And I came home to this.
我不是个容易惊慌的人
Now, I don't panic easily...
但这样很不对劲吧？
but it's weird, right?
我们能看看吗？
Mind if we look around?
请便
Please.
你们住在这里多久了？
How long have you two been here?
九月就满两年了，之前住在纽约
Two years in September. We used to live in New York.
纽约市？
City?
对，我以前是作家，我们都是
Yeah, I was a writer. We were both writers.
你们为什么搬回来？
Why did you all move back here?
我妈生病了
My mom got sick.
抱歉，她现在还好吗？
Oh, I'm sorry. How is she?
她过世了
She's dead.
我很遗憾
I'm so sorry.
你现在做什么工作？
What do you do now, for work?
我和妹妹玛戈在市区经营酒吧
My sister Margo and I own The Bar downtown.
那间“酒吧”啊
Oh, The Bar.
叫“酒吧”的酒吧，很形而上
Love the name. Very meta.
谢谢
Thanks.
都是些好东西
Pretty things.
别乱跑
Stay.
这里是我的书房
My office, here.
很漂亮的衣服
Beautiful dress.
今晚要约会？
Date night? It's our anniversary.
今天是我们的结婚纪念日
Hmm.
这边是客房
It's a guest bedroom, there.
猫的房间在后面
Cat's room on the end.
我找过那边了
I checked up here.
这边是厨房
This is the kitchen...
很明显
obviously.
这是我老婆的书房
This is my wife's office.
爱咪的书房
Amy's office.
“哈佛大学”
她很厉害啊
Wow. Impressive gal.
对，我应该要担心吗？
Yeah. Should I be concerned?
我记得这些书
I remember these.
“神奇的爱咪”
我以前很喜欢这些书
I loved these books.
等等
Wait a minute.
你太太就是神奇的爱咪？
Your wife is Amazing Amy?
对，就是她
Yeah. She is.
真厉害
Wow.
“2007年2月24日”
他妈的神奇爱咪他妈的要结婚了
Amazing-fucking-Amy is getting fucking married.
所以今晚才有这场活动
That's how the night started.
平凡有缺点的真爱咪嫉妒着天之骄子
With me, regular, flawed, real Amy,
“该做的事就要做得聪明俐落”
jealous, as always, of the golden child.
完美聪明的神奇爱咪他妈的要结婚了
Perfect, brilliant, Amazing Amy,who's getting fucking married.
我10岁的时候放弃了大提琴
When I was 10, I quit cello.
在下一本书里，爱咪成了小神童
In the next book, Amazing Amy became a prodigy.
你打排球吗？
Did you play volleyball?
一年级时被退队了
I got cut, freshman year.
结果她进了大学代表队
She made varsity.
你什么时候养过狗？
When did you have a dog?
是她养了狗
She got the dog.
普多斯让爱咪更平易近人
Puddles made her more relatable.
哇
Wow.
我喜欢你爸妈
I love your parents...
但他们有时真的很混蛋
but they really can be assholes.
尼克  - 伯父
Nick! Sir!
谢谢你来参加
Hey, thanks for coming, man.
没什么
No problem.
亲爱的
Hey, sweetheart.
今天是你妈的大日子
Big night for your mom.
如果你跟几个记者和部落客聊聊
It would mean so much if you would talk to a few reporters...
让他们瞧瞧爱咪本色就太好了
bloggers, give them a little Amy color.
大家都想听你的想法
People wanna hear from you.
我们不能待太久  - 没问题
We can't stay long. Fantastic.
最多只要15分钟
Fifteen minutes, tops.
我的豪宅跟信托基金都靠他们
This is why I have my brownstone.
不能抱怨
My trust fund. I know I can't complain.
你爸妈根本剽窃了你的创作
Your parents literally plagiarized your childhood.
不，他们提出改良版然后四处兜售
No, they improved upon it and then peddled it to the masses.
我以为你会配合结婚主题穿白衣服
I thought you were gonna wear white to match the wedding theme.
我觉得那样超诡异
I thought that would be creepy.
“该做的事就要做得…”
"if it's worth doing, it's worth doing..."
够了，我知道这句话，不用提醒我
Hold up! I know how this ends. Don't tell me.
你帅，尼克
You're very cute, Nick.
你知道今晚怎么让你爸开心
Amy, you know what would make Dad's night.
我会的
Oh, I'm on it.
我超爱陌生人戳我痛处的
I love having strangers pick at my scabs.
我很好奇
I'm curious whether...
神奇爱咪结婚是否让你难受？
it's difficult for you to see Amazing Amy heading down the aisle.
还有庆祝假婚礼的这个盛大派对
And this big party celebrating this fictional wedding.
因为据我所知你还未婚
Because it's my understanding you are not married.
是这样吗？
Is that correct?
没错，神奇爱咪总是早我一步
Correct.Amazing Amy has always been one step ahead of me.
抱歉打扰各位，但我还有几个问题
Excuse me. I'm sorry, I just have a few questions.
是你
It's you.
我来这里完全是公事公办
I'm here in a strictly journalistic capacity.
请问你愉快地和尼克邓恩约会多久了？
Now, you had the distinct pleasure of dating Nick Dunne for how long?
神奇的两年  - 神奇的两年
Two magical years.
在这段时间里你曾多次
In the course of that time, you've had the opportunity...
展现你的亲切可人，例如…
to perform such gracious gestures as...
不在尼克把“奎宁”念成“圭宁”时纠正他
not correcting Nick when he pronounced "quinoa" as "kween-o-a."
这是可以理解的错误
An understandable mistake.
但他还以为那是一种鱼
He also thought it was a fish.
他也以为人造起司是真的乳酪
He thinks Velveeta is a cheese.
尼克的妈妈每次看到你的时候
You also manage to appear shocked and delighted...
都会即兴演唱“纽约纽约”这首歌
when Nick's elderly mother breaks into an impromptu rendition...
但你依旧假装自己又惊又喜
of New York, New York, every time she sees you.
“这袋骨头鞋”
These bag of bone shoes
真的很吓人
That's just frightening.
你也帮尼克买了他的第一把剪刀
You also bought Nick his very first pair of scissors.
还有成对的订书机
And matching stapler.
爱咪艾略特，你不只是神奇
Amy Elliott, you are more than amazing.
你冰雪聪明而且毫不势利
You are brilliant, yet entirely un-snobby.
你启发我，你总带来惊奇
You challenge me. You surprise me.
另外给读者的有趣小知识
And, fun fact for the readers...
你的阴道是世界级的
you have a world-class vagina.
我的同行说你还没结婚
My colleagues tell me that you are not yet married.
这是真的吗？
Is that correct?
我还没结婚
I'm not.
我们不如做点改变
Isn't it time we fixed that?
于是
And then...
那天晚上一点都不糟糕了
the night wasn't so bad anymore.
完成了，从清单划掉
And it's done. Crossed off the list.
通常失踪案不会那么快成立
Now, normally, we would not treat this as a missing persons case so quick...
不过以你家的状况
but given the scene at your house...
还有最近暴力犯罪直线上升的情况
and given our spike in violent crime of late...
我们会特别审慎处理这个案子
we are gonna take this very, very seriously.
那很好
Okay. Good.
监识科去你家了，你有别的地方住吗？
We've got forensics over at your place. You got somewhere to stay?
我可以住妹妹家  - 好
I could stay at my sister's. Okay.
我们在追踪爱咪的电话和信用卡
We're tracking Amy's phone, her credit cards.
接着会组织搜索行动，发传单
We will organize searches, put up flyers.
明天会开记者会  - 记者会？
We're gonna hold a press conference tomorrow. You're having a press conference?
我们要把消息放出去
I wanna get the word out, right?
对，但我觉得自己好像在演“法网游龙”
Yeah, it's just all of a sudden I feel like I'm on a Law & Order episode.
这种案子就是跟时间赛跑
Time is of the essence in these cases.
不过你要不要先打电话给律师？
But, that said, do you wanna wait and call a lawyer?
不需要，我只想帮上忙
Absolutely not. I just wanna help.
所以你和爱咪住在这里两年了
So, you and Amy have been here two years.
你顾店  - 我是“酒吧”老板
You tend bar... I own The Bar.
还在米尔谷社区大学教创意写作
And I teach creative writing at MVCC.
你们没小孩？  - 还没
No kids? Not yet.
爱咪平常在做什么？
So, what does Amy do most days?
有这么多学位的女人都在做什么？
A woman with all those degrees, what does she do?
我不知道，她总有事做
I don't know. She keeps busy.
做什么？
Doing what?
她很喜欢看书
She's a voracious reader.
所以她手里总有一本书
So, she's always got a book in her hand.
但一天可是很漫长的
Well, days can get long.
我认识几个中午就开始喝酒的主妇
I know a few housewives, that evening glass of wine starts coming at noon.
或者药吃不停
Or prescription pills.
上礼拜有个标准好主妇
Just last week, we had a soccer mom.
嗑止痛药嗑到ㄎ一ㄤ掉
Nice lady. Got her teeth kicked in over some OxyContin.
购物中心倒闭后半个镇的人都失业了
Ever since that mall went bust, half the town is out of work.
毒品暴力事件抓不胜抓
We cannot keep up with the drug violence.
我确定爱咪没有吸毒
I'm pretty sure that's not it.
我们能跟爱咪的朋友谈谈吗？
Has Amy got friends we can talk to?
额~
Um...
她没什么朋友
No, not really.
没朋友？整个镇上都没有？
No friends? This whole town?
她跟我妈感情很好，但她过世了
She was very close with my mom, before she passed away.
这里游民的问题很严重
You know, we have a pretty serious homeless problem...
我们附近很多
in our neighborhood.
你们应该去查一查
I think maybe you guys should check that out.
我们会的
We'll look into that.
你今天大约11：00到酒吧
You got to The Bar around 11:00 today.
在那之前你在哪？只是例行问话
Where were you before that? Just to cross that out.
我在家
Well, I was home.
我9：30出门，带着咖啡和报纸
I left at 9:30, I got a cup of coffee, a newspaper.
到索耶沙滩去看报纸
I went to Sawyer Beach and read the news.
你是自己去的吗？
Did you visit with anyone there?
我去索耶沙滩就是图个清静
I kind of go to Sawyer Beach for the solitude.
所以你太太在这里没有朋友
So, your wife has no friends here.
她是不是有点高傲？
Is she kinda standoffish?
念常春藤名校？会不会常得罪人？
Ivy League? Rubs people the wrong way?
她是纽约客
She's from New York. Oh.
她很复杂，标准很高
She's complicated. She's got very high standards.
是A型人格吗？
Type A?
如果你不是那种人，很容易被搞疯
That can make you crazy if you're not like that.
你好像比较慵懒，是B型人格
You seem pretty laid-back. Type B.
说到这里，爱咪的血型是什么？
Speaking of which, Amy's blood type?
老天，我不知道，我要回家找找
God, I don't know. I'd have to look it up at the house.
你不知道她的交友状况
You don't know if she has friends...
白天在干嘛
you don't know what she does all day...
也不知道你老婆的血型
and you don't know your wife's blood type.
你确定你们结婚了？
Sure you all are married?
她可能是O型
Uh... Maybe it's type O.
她的父母都在纽约吗？  - 对
Where are her folks? New York? Yeah.
明天记者会时他们能到吗？
Can they get here time for this press conference tomorrow?
明天？我不知道，我还没联络他们
Tomorrow? I have no idea. I haven't talked to them.
你还没联络你岳父母？
You haven't called your wife's parents yet?
这里没有讯号，我又一直在跟你讲话
You can't get a signal in this building.  I've been in here talking to you.
尼克，请立刻联络他们
Call them, please, Nick. Now.
好啊
Fine.
我应该知道我太太的血型吗？
Should I know my wife's blood type?
不用
No.
对不起，玛莉贝丝
I apologize, Marybeth.
我不知道出了什么事
I didn't know what was going on.
我人在警察局
Now I'm at the station...
警察在我们家，情况严重
and the cops are at the house,and it's serious
我得联络你们
and I'm calling you.
现在事情很多而且一团乱
There's a lot of things that are being juggled right now.
我和隆妲邦妮警探在一起
I'm standing right next to Detective Rhonda Boney...
她是主要调查员，她…
who's the lead investigator on this and she's...
我岳母想跟你说话
My mother-in-law would like to speak with you.
我是邦妮警探
This is Detective Boney.
我想回家
I wanna go home.
我不懂为什么我得在这里
I don't know why I have to be here.
我不想在这里，我想回家
I don't wanna be here. I wanna go home.
爸？
Dad?
他是我爸，怎么回事？
This is my father. What's going on?
是吗？你是尼克邓恩？
Really? You're Nick Dunne?
我们一整个下午都在联络你
We've been trying to get a hold of you all afternoon.
我一直在这里，我太太失踪了
I've been right there. My wife is missing.
贱人  - 别这样
Bitch. Don't.
你父亲午餐后就从安适山丘跑出来了
Your father wandered out of Comfort Hill after lunch.
我们在79号公路上发现迷失的他
We found him walking Route 79, disoriented.
我们一直打电话联络你
We've been trying to call you for the last...
这里收不到讯号
I don't get a cell signal in this building.
我就在六公尺之外的房间里
I've been sitting 20 feet away from you.
先生，请不要用这种语气跟我说话
Sir, please don't take that tone with me.
又蠢又笨又丑的贱人
Stupid, dumb, ugly bitch.
爸，别说了
Dad, stop.
你要开车载他回去吗？
You wanna drive him home?
这应该是个好主意，谢谢
I think that would be wise. Thanks.
语音信箱已满
This voice mailbox is currently full.
该死
Fuck.
“安适山丘安养中心”
把你的脏手拿开
Oh, get your fucking hands off me.
谢谢
Thanks.
“2009年7月5日”
所有人都再三告诫我们
Everyone told us and told us and told us...
婚姻并不容易
marriage is hard work.
需要妥协和努力
And compromise and more work.
“进入此门之人必放弃希望”
"Abandon all hope, ye who enter."
“年轻的爱咪确实逐渐放弃希望
"When young Amy's hope did wane...
她在此游荡…”
"she wandered here..."
才不是，我和尼克不是这样
Well, it's not true. Not for me and Nick.
“寻找珍奥斯汀”
"...in search of Jane."
这两年对我们来说
With us, two years...
好得不得了
it's just good.
奥斯汀
Austen. Hmm.
你是孤独的少年，只有书中人了解你
You were an alienated teen and only Elizabeth Bennet understood you.
你看那个
Look at that.
我的天
My God.
你这个淘气的小骚货
You naughty minx.
严格来说我们应该在下一站才开干
Well, technically, we are supposed to fuck at the next stop.
对，这样才符合传统
Yeah, in keeping with tradition.
但我可能愿意破例一次
But I might be willing to bend the rules this once.
天佑珍奥斯汀
God bless Jane Austen.
我很有热忱，你看连饼干都这么说
I'm enthusiastic.Look at that. It's confirmed by the...
谢谢
Oh, thank you.
第二年，棉婚
Year two. Cotton.
我们说过普通床单配不上我们的性爱
We had that joke that our sex was too good for ordinary.
所以这是两千织的…
So, these are 2,000 thread-count...
我们太可爱了，真该揍自己一拳
We're so cute.I wanna punch us in the face.
真的很不错，满好的
That's pretty great. I mean, that is pretty great.
他们有没有问你要不要找律师？
Did they ask if you wanted a lawyer?
我不需要律师，我来就好
I don't need a lawyer. Here, I'll do this.
他们有没有问爱咪的私人生活
Well, did they ask personal stuff about Amy?
他们有问啊
You know, they asked...
为什么她没有朋友？
why didn't she have any friends?
你怎么说？
What did you say?
我说她很复杂  - 尼克
I said she was complicated. Nick!
大家都知道“复杂”代表“贱人”
Everyone knows "complicated" is code for "bitch."
老天，我觉得好糟
Oh, God. I feel sick.
谢谢
Thanks.
这件事真的很奇怪
It's so bizarre.
这就是会发生在爱咪身上的事
It seems like the kind of thing that would happen to Amy.
她总是会吸引…
She always attracts...
戏剧性的遭遇？
Drama?
只有我们，你可以直说
You can say it. It's just me and you.
虽然我不喜欢和爱咪相处
Just because I don't like to be around Amy...
不表示我不关心她
doesn't mean I don't care about her.
总之，带走她的人一定会带她回来
Anyway, whoever took her is bound to bring her back.
警探？不好意思
Detective? Excuse me.
我是诺耶儿霍桑，爱咪最好的朋友
I'm Noelle Hawthorne. I'm Amy's best friend.
太好了，你住在哪里？
Well, great. Where do you live, Noelle?
从这里过去五间，1032号
Five doors down. 1032.
很好，我想跟你谈谈
Wonderful. I would love to talk to you.
我半小时后过去可以吗？
Can I come by in half an hour?
有什么进展吗？  - 抱歉
Y'all know anything yet? I'm sorry.
我这边还要忙，但30分钟就好了
I got guys on the clock in here.But you give me 30 minutes.
但到时候我要帮小孩洗澡
But that's usually bath time.
我们可以边洗边聊
Well, we'll talk in between shampoos.
好，你发现什么了？
All right. So, what do you got?
厨房里绝对有血迹
It was definitely blood spatter you saw in the kitchen.
很正常，厨房总有刀子
Normally, kitchen,
准备食物的工具
knives, food prep.
不算奇怪，但血迹位置有点太高
Not that weird, but that is awfully high.
所以我要做鲁米诺测试
So, I'm gonna order a luminol sweep.
好
Well, okay.
真有意思
Mmm, interesting.
怎么了？
What's that?
这间房子的租约和车子都是她的名字
House is rented in her name.Car's in her name.
信用卡，水电费，电话帐单全都是
Credit cards, utilities, phone bill, all in her name.
连他的酒吧都在她的名下
Even his bar's in her name.
我不知道这有什么好惊讶的
I don't know that that's so surprising.
是没有，只是很丢脸
No. But it is humiliating.
你找到什么？
What you got?
跟她的私人衣物放在一起
It's with her unmentionables.
我们有第一个线索了
Well, we have our first clue.
“线索一”
“7月6日  事发之后一日”
“阿斯匹灵”
我得冲个澡
I have to take a shower.
不行，你整晚没睡
No, don't. You've been up all night.
你就要看起来整晚没睡的样子
You wanna look like you've been up all night.
今天小心点，好吗？
Hey, be careful today, okay?
为什么这么说？
That's a weird thing to say.
你每次不高兴就喝酒
Well, when you're upset, you bottle up.
会看起来很愤怒
You can seem angry, like...
拜托别说“跟爸一样”
Please don't say, "Like Dad."
不然你就会进入讨好模式
Or else you swing into your momma's-boy charm offensive...
感觉很肤浅
and that can feel glib. Perfect.
太好了
Perfect.
我会小心在这情绪刀锋上保持平衡
I'll balance on the exact fucking edge of your emotional razor.
这样吧，你就…
Okay. Just be...
做自己？
Myself?
收入金额捐赠西郡四健会
...sponsoring a raffle to benefit West County 4H...
并赞助密苏里大学橄榄球季票
and raffling season tickets for Mizzou football.
请在飞翅屋或各地三州轮胎行购买
Buy your tickets at the Wing Hut or local Tri-State Tire stores.
你的岳父母赶上了
Your in-laws made it.
瑞德  - 老兄
Hi, Rand. Hey, man.
我是邦妮警探
I'm Detective Boney.
我是他双胞胎妹妹玛戈
I'm the twin. Margo.
我们昨天还打网球，我无法原谅自己
We played tennis yesterday, Nick. I just can't get over it.
玛莉贝丝，我很抱歉
Marybeth, I am really sorry.
我就知道你们不该搬回来
I knew you never should have moved back here.
我们别无选择
We didn't have a lot of choice.
我们都很担心也很害怕
We are all worried. We are all scared.
但我们都在这里，会一起找到爱咪
But we are all here now.And we will find Amy, together.
“失踪  爱咪邓恩”
我先说话，然后换你们吗？
Should I just go first, and then you guys can say something?
好
Good.
各位都知道，我妻子爱咪艾略特邓恩
As you know, my wife, Amy Elliott Dunne...
在7月5日早上从我们家里失踪
disappeared from our home on the morning of July 5th...
情况相当可疑
under suspicious circumstances.
大声一点
Louder!
如果各位有任何消息
If anyone out there, uh, has any information...
请与我们联系
please come forward.
谢谢
Thank you.
我是瑞德艾略特，玛莉贝丝是我妻子
I'm Rand Elliott. My wife, Marybeth Elliott.
我应该说我的名字吗？
Should I have said my name?
爱咪是我们的独生女
Amy is our only child.
她聪明，美丽又温柔
She's bright, she's beautiful. She's kind.
她就是神奇的爱咪
She really is Amazing Amy.
有数百万的读者
You know, there are millions of people out there...
都和她一起长大，关心着她
who grew up with her and care about her.
我们关心她，我们爱她
We care about her, we love her.
我们只希望她回来
And we just want her back.
爱咪是获奖的学者
Amy is a decorated scholar.
她在新闻界有成功的事业
She forged a successful career in journalism.
她回到丈夫的故乡
She returned here to her husband's hometown...
而且在异乡努力生活
and she made a life in her adopted home.
现在爱咪需要你的帮助
Now, Amy needs your help.
我们在卓睿酒店成立了义工中心
We're establishing a volunteer headquarters at the Drury Lodge.
提供线索请拨1-855-4-AMY-TIPS
We have a hotline, 1-855-4-AMY-TIPS.
网站网址是www.FindAmazingAmy.com
And our website is wvvw.FindAmazingAmy.com.
邓恩先生  - 艾略特先生
- Mr. Dunne! - Mr. Elliott!
邓恩先生，有任何谋杀的迹象吗？
Mr. Dunne, any signs of foul play?
艾略特先生
Mr. Elliott
你上次和女儿交谈是何时？
when was the last time you spoke to your daughter?
微笑
Smile.
今天结束了，谢谢各位
That's all for now. Thank you.
爱咪的异性缘非常好
Amy is the kind of girl who attracts admirers.
对吧，尼克？
Right, Nick?
无庸置疑
Yeah, definitely.
以往有过前例
And we've had instances...
事情曾经…    - 变得可怕
where things got... Scary.
你知道戴西柯林斯吗？
Do you know about Desi Collings?
我知道戴西柯林斯的事
Yeah, I know all about Desi Collings.
他很执着
He was obsessed.
爱咪大二跟他分手时，他试图自杀
He attempted suicide after Amy broke up with him sophomore year.
我们被迫申请禁制令
We had to file a restraining order.
是高中的事了，20年前吗？
This would be high school? Twenty years ago?
但他最近搬到圣路易斯，2小时车程
But he recently moved to St. Louis.That's just two hours away.
不过他本来就是圣路易斯人
To be fair, he is from St. Louis.
另外还有汤米欧哈拉
We also have Tommy O'Hara.
是八年前在纽约的事
This is only eight years ago, in New York.
她跟他分手，他开始动手
She broke up with him, he got very physical.
所以她提告了  - 罪名是什么？
- She filed charges. - What was the charge?
性侵，胁迫，殴打，哪一个？
Sexual assault, threat, battery, what?
我只知道满糟的
I only know it was bad.
我不知道这件事  - 好了
- I didn't know this. - Okay.
谢谢你们
Thank you.
有比较近期的情况吗？
Uh, anything more recent?
就我所知没有
Not that I know of.
尼克，你有时间吗？
Hey, Nick? You got a minute?
有
Yeah.
你可以想像我们的困惑
Imagine our confusion.
一个失踪案
A missing persons case...
我们在你太太的更衣室发现一个“线索”
and in your wife's dressing room...
这是我们纪念日的传统
we find an envelope marked "clue." That's for our anniversary.
我太太会设计寻宝游戏
My wife does these treasure hunts.
希望你能告诉我这个线索的意义
I'm hoping you can tell me what this means.
你要解开爱咪的寻宝游戏？
You want to solve Amy's treasure hunt?
这样有助于追踪她失踪前的行动
It'll help me track Amy's movements before she disappeared.
当然可以，好
Of course. Okay.
“虽然这地方狭小不华丽
"Although this spot couldn't be tighter...
却是我心爱作家的一方天地”
"it's a cozy room for my favorite writer."
我知道答案
I know this one!
虽然这地方狭小不华丽
Although this spot couldn't be any tighter...
却是我心爱作家的一方天地
it's a cozy room for my favorite writer.
课后辅导别怕我说不
After-school meeting, don't mind if I do.
也许我能教你两三步
Maybe I'll teach you a thing or two.
“线索二”
上面说什么？
Well, well. What does it say?
线索二
Clue two.
“帅哥，让我们卧底去
"Hey, handsome man, let's go undercover.
你扮间谍,我是伴侣”
"You'll be the spy, and I'll be his lover.
“写书灵感”
"Let's head on over...
“一起去吧 到那褐色小屋见
"to the little brown house.
我们是干柴烈火的热情床伴”
"We'll play hot, doting husband, sweet, loving spouse."
这是你的吗？
These yours?
不是
No.
但你看过第一条线索了
But you read the first clue.
风流教授俏学生
Randy professor, naughty student.
我脸都红了
I blush.
我和前夫只会交换卡片
Me and my ex just swapped cards.
褐色小屋在哪里？
Where's this little brown house?
我不知道
I have no idea.
“协寻爱咪”
你好
Hello?
我是尼可拉斯邓恩
Nicholas Dunne.
这是我父亲威廉邓恩名下的房子
Under my father's name, William Dunne.
“线索三”
我太太第一只宠物？需要吗？你关掉吧…
My wife's first pet? Is this necessary?Can you just turn the bell...
对，我知道
Yeah, I know.
是…
It's, uh... It's, uh...
是帕多斯还是普多斯？
Uh...It's "Puddles," right? Or is it "Poodles?"
没事了
We're good.
陌生人你好
Hello, stranger.
没想到会在这里碰到你
Fancy meeting you here.
这是你爸爸的房子吗？
It's your dad's house, right?
你在跟踪我吗？
Are you following me?
你在做什么？
What you doing?
就像你说的，这是我爸的房子
Like you said, it's my dad's house.
我一周来一次，确认房子没烧掉
I come by once a week, make sure the place hasn't burned down.
看起来没事
But it looks okay.
我陪你走出去
I'll walk you out.
你知道吗
You know...
我以为这里可能就是褐色小屋
I thought maybe this was the little brown house.
线索里说的那个
From the clue.
不，这里是蓝色的
Nope. Still blue.
想像我是个非常坏的坏女孩
Picture me, I'm a girl who's very, very bad.
你要惩罚我，要对我使坏
I need to be punished, and by "punished," I mean "had."
你把五周年的好东西都藏在这儿
It's where you keep goodies for anniversary five.
那就打开门仔细瞧瞧
"So open the door, and look alive."
贱人
Bitch!
“2010年7月18日”
你想测试婚姻的弱点吗？
Want to test your marriage for weak spots?
经济萧条加一
Add one recession...
工作减二
subtract two jobs.
有效得令人惊讶
It's surprisingly effective.
答应我，我们永远不会变成那样
Promise me we'll never be like them.
哪样？
Like who?
我们认识的那些糟糕夫妻
All those awful couples we know.
把丈夫当成跳舞小猴的太太
Those wives who treat their men like dancing monkeys...
总想训练他们，唯命是从
to be trained and paraded.
还有把太太当成公路警察的丈夫
Husbands who treat their wives like the highway patrol...
老是想骗过她们，躲开她们
to be out-foxed and avoided.
我可能要被解雇了
I think I'm gonna be laid off.
现在经济不好，遇到了我们再处理
We're in a recession. If it happens, we'll deal with it.
我可能是下一个
I'll probably be next.
我们还有彼此
We have each other.
其他事都只是过眼云烟而已
Everything else is background noise.
你是最特别的
You are exceptional.
该我了
My turn.
出版社放弃我爸妈了，他们债台高筑
My parents' publisher dropped them...and they're in debt up to their ears.
真糟糕
That's terrible.
他们要从我的信托基金借钱
And they need to borrow from my trust fund.
借多少？
How much?
将近一百万美元
Almost a million.
那差不多是全部了
That's almost all of it.
这时候你该说“其他都是过眼云烟”
This is where you say, "Everything else is background noise."
爱咪，如果你被解雇
Amy, if you're laid off...
我也被解雇
and I'm laid off...
我说了我会借他们
I said I'd do it.
没跟我商量？
Without talking to me?
因为…  - 向你决定
Well, it's... Your call.
严格来说那是他们的钱
...their money, technically.
你知道吗，你说得对
You know what? You're right.
其他事都是过眼云烟
Everything else is just background noise.
我回来了
Hey-
还在打电动？
More games?
对，我想杀几个人
Yeah, I just wanted to shoot some folks.
你干嘛买笔电？
What's the laptop for?
玩电脑啊
Laptop-ing.
是喔
Oh, I see.
你没跟我商量就给你爸妈87万9千
You can give your parents $879,000 without talking to me...
但我连买个电动玩具都要经过你同意
but God forbid I buy a video game without getting your permission.
你花了很多钱
You are spending a lot.
你不相信我，你不相信我的判断
You don't trust me. You don't trust my judgment.
你当然不相信我的动机
You certainly don't trust my intention.
你在说什么？
What are you talking about?
这不就是婚前协议书的基本原则吗？
That's the basic tenet of a prenup, isn't it?
你为什么又拿这件事来呛我？
Why are you throwing that in my face again?
因为很容易
Because it's easy to throw.
尼克，我不明白
Nick, I don't get it.
你为什么要我变成我不想要的样子
I don't get why you're daring me to be someone I don't wanna be.
我不想当个唠叨的控制狂疯女人
The nagging shrew. The controlling bitch.
我不是那种人，我是你妻子
I'm not that person. I'm your wife.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我不知道该怎么办，我没有失业过
I just don't know how to do this. I've never not had a job.
我做过汉堡，我漆过房子
I flipped burgers, I painted houses.
你会找到新工作的
You'll get another job.
小戈
Hi, Go.
什么？说慢点，怎么了？
What? Hold on. What?
突然间  - 慢慢来，怎么回事？
And suddenly... Slow down, what is it?
我知道一切都在恶化
...I knew everything was about to get worse.
告诉我出了什么事
Okay, tell me what's wrong.
“7月7日  事发之后二日
祝福你，尼克  - 神父
Bless you, Nick. Father.
汤姆，市长
Hey, Tom. Mayor!
尼克，很高兴看见你
Nick, good to see you.
看见你真好
Good to see you.
各位好
Hey, guys, hey-
裘迪  - 尼克
Jodie. Nick.
我们会找到她的
Oh, we'll find her. Mmm-hmm.
你看起来糟透了
You look like hammered shit.
谢谢
Oh, thank you.
你看过那个戴眼镜的家伙吗？
You ever see that guy in the glasses before?
别担心，所有进出的人我们都有录影
Don't worry. We videotape everybody that comes in and out of these things.
因为这里有很多…
I mean, you tend to get a lot of...
好心人？
Do-gooders?
怪人
Freaks.
我想问你
Hey, I meant to ask you.
认识诺耶儿霍桑吗？
Noelle Hawthorne?
跟你们住同条街，爱咪最好的朋友
She lives on your street. Amy's best friend.
我没听过诺耶儿霍桑这个名字
I've never heard the name Noelle Hawthorne.
她跟她老公生了三胞胎
She and her husband have triplets.
是她啊
Oh.
对，我们应该在街上跟她们打过招呼
Yeah, we might say hi to them on the street.
但我不会说她是爱咪最好的朋友
But "best friend"? No.
不好意思，等我一下
Excuse me, one sec.
他的样子彷佛诺耶儿是个陌生人
He acted like Noelle was a complete stranger.
他当然会这样
Of course he did.
这两个是你的
Look, these two are yours.
你看，他刻意的想当个好人
Oh, look. He's being a good guy...
所以大家当然会觉得他是个好人
so everybody can see him being a good guy.
你真的不喜欢他，对吧？
Oh, you really don't like him, do you?
他有什么好的？
What's to like?
语音信箱已满，请按1…
This mailbox is currently full.Press one to...
是尼克吗？我是香娜凯莉
Nick? I just wanted to introduce myself. My name's Shawna Kelly.
你的遭遇让我很遗憾
I am so sorry for your troubles.
谢谢你，你真好心
Thank you. That's kind.
你吃过东西了吗？
Are you remembering to eat?
我吃了不少冷盘肉
Well, a lot of cold cuts.
让我用最拿手的玉米片香鸡派来招待你
I'm gonna fix you up my world-famous chicken Frito pie.
你真好心，但不需要
That's very kind and very unnecessary.
你一定要保持体力
You have to keep your strength.
麻烦你…
Would you...
说“玉米片香鸡派”
say, "Chicken Frito pie!"
听我说
Um...You know what?
请你删除那张照片可以吗？
Would you delete that picture for me?
拍得很好啊  - 我知道
It's a nice photo. I know it is.
但请你帮个忙
But just do me a favor.
好不好？
Will you?
你可以离开然后拜托删除那张照片吗？
Would you go ahead and please delete that picture?
只要按下…
You just press...
你有什么问题？
What is wrong with you?
别让人看到…
Could you please not share that with anyone?
我高兴给谁看就给谁看
I will share it with whomever I please.
老兄  - 什么事？
Dude. Yeah?
玛莉贝丝气疯了
Marybeth is pissed.
为什么？
Why?
玛莉贝丝？
Marybeth?
你他妈的好像校园偶像一样
It's like you're the goddamn Homecoming King.
我妈妈很重视礼貌
It was important to my mother that I be polite...
我一定要体贴，绅士
I be considerate, I be a gentleman.
你好像乐在其中
It looked like you were having fun.
我活在恶梦里啊
I am in a nightmare!
我只是很感谢那些…
All I'm trying to do is be nice...
来帮忙寻找爱咪的人
to the people who are volunteering to help find Amy.
你说得对
You're right.
我很抱歉
And I'm sorry.
老天，这里闻起来像大便一样
My God, this place literally smells like feces.
你们有找到很贵的高尔夫球杆吗？
In your searches, did you find any golf clubs, real fancy?
没有
No.
全新的电吉他呢？
How about a brand new Stratocaster?
没有那种东西
No, nothing like that.
好吧
Well, all right.
这台电视多大？不是65寸的
How big's that TV? It's not 65-inch.
比那小多了
No, it's nowhere near that.
好
Okay-
饲料在哪？  - 什么？
Kibble? Excuse me?
尼克要我帮他喂猫
He asked me to feed his cat.
橱柜里有一些
Oh, I saw some in the pantry.
邦妮警探，吉尔宾警官？我是诺耶儿
Detective Boney, Officer Gilpin? Noelle Hawthorne!
我知道你们在里面
I know y'all are in there!
请你们带霍桑女士和小孩回街上好吗？
Would you please escort Miss Hawthorne and her children back out to the street?
邦妮警探
Detective Boney!
提醒她这里可能是犯罪现场
Just remind her it is a possible crime scene.
妻子失踪了，这男人还笑得这么开心
Look at that pie-eating grin from a guy whose wife is missing.
你还好吗？  - 超棒的
How are you doing? Terrific.
玛莉贝丝怎么样？
How's Marybeth?
她糟透了
She's a wreck.
你呢？
And you?
好得不得了
Awesome.
听我说
Hey...
你真的什么都说了吗？
have you told me everything?
当然
Of course.
所有事？
Everything?
你为什么这样问我？
Why would you even ask me that?
从爱咪失踪那天，你走进酒吧之后
Ever since you walked into The Bar that morning Amy went missing,
你变得很奇怪  - 我是很奇怪
you seem off. I am off.
大家都在关注我，把情绪丢给我
Everybody's examining me and projecting their shit on me.
我只是想来跟你喝杯啤酒
All I want is to come over here, have a beer with you...
不用被批评
and not be judged.
可以吗？
Can we do that?
当然
Of course.
你知道吗，我一直在想…
You know what I keep thinking?
如果妈还在就好了？
If Mom were here?
是啊，好像我才12岁一样
Yeah. Like I'm 12.
尼克，妈可以解决这情况
Nick, Mom would fix it.
我要吃点过敏药然后去睡觉
I'm gonna go Benadryl myself to sleep.
我爱你  - 我爱你
Love you. Love you.
“2010年9月23日”
接下来是个奇怪的新句子
So, here's a strange, new sentence.
我是密苏里人了
I am a Missourian.
再见，爸
Mmm, bye, Dad.
我们没钱没工作没未来
No money, no jobs, no prospects.
然后小戈联络我们
And then, we heard from Go.
莫琳妈妈
Mama Maureen...
第四期乳癌
Stage 4 breast cancer.
所以我们搬到密苏里
So, we moved to Missouri.
我不在意
I don't mind.
我只是希望他先问过我
I just wish he'd asked.
“欢迎”
“吉屋出租”
尼克很高兴可以回到故乡
Nick is happy to be home.
但我不知道他高不高兴我跟他一起
But I don't know if he's happy I'm with him.
我觉得我像他不小心带回家的大包袱
I feel like something he loaded by mistake.
必要的时候可以被他弃如敝屣
Something to be jettisoned, if necessary.
我是可抛弃的
Something disposable.
我觉得自己可以消失
I feel like I could disappear.
“我在外面”
我的天哪
Oh, my God!
我在电视上看到你  - 我知道
I saw you on TV. Okay.
太可怕了  - 我知道
It's so crazy. Yeah, I know.
她凭空消失吗？  - 她只是不见了
She just vanished? She's just gone.
我好担心你  - 你都到哪里去了？
I've been so worried about you. Where have you been?
我打了一百通电话，你要接啊
I called you a hundred times. You gotta pick up your phone!
我在排演
Rehearsals.
什么？
What?
音乐剧“上帝的魅力”
Godspell.
我妹妹睡在隔壁房间
My sister's asleep in the other room.
我非见你不可
I needed to see you.
我知道这样不对
I know this is a bad idea.
跟我说你爱我？
Can you at least tell me you love me?
我爱你，但是我们现在要很小心
I do love you, but we have to be really careful right now.
我一直好担心
Oh, I've been so scared.
排演的时候？
Between rehearsals?
你跟我说要有自己的生活
You told me I needed to have my own life.
我知道
I know.
我们得停了
We need to stop.
我需要你
I need you.
摸我
Touch me.
停下来，过来这里
Stop it. Come here.
坐下
Sit down.
好
Okay-
你有没有跟别人提过我们的事？
Did you, by any chance, tell anybody anything about us?
在简讯或脸书上都算
Even in texting, or on Facebook.
脸书？我都改用易付卡了
Facebook? I use the disposable phone.
你都用现金买礼物，我不是笨蛋
You buy my presents in cash. I'm not stupid, Nick.
我知道，你有红内裤留在我办公室吗？
I know, sweetie. Did you leave a pair of red panties in my office?
可能有吧，那最好是我的
I don't know. Maybe. They better be mine.
甜心，认真想
Sweetheart, think.
我不知道，我得回去查红内裤存货
I don't know. I'd have to check my red panty inventory.
安蒂，我拜托你认真点好不好？
Andie, I need you to take this seriously, okay?
这是我们最后一次见面，除非…
This is the last time we're gonna see each other, until...
除非什么？
Until when?
除非够安全了
Until it's safe.
你说你要离婚的
You were going to get a divorce.
绝对不要再说这句话
Never say that out loud again.
好，我很抱歉
Okay. I'm sorry.
我不想吵架
I don't wanna fight.
我只想跟你在一起
I just wanna be with you.
安蒂，拜托
Andie, oh, please...
我只要这样就好
That's all I want.
不行
I can't.
这是我们最后一次在一起
It's our last time together.
我们要好好把握
Let's make the most of it.
很快，然后你就一定得走了
Real quick, but then you have to go.
“2011年10月2日”
我先生越来越失控
My husband has come undone.
我们搬回密苏里照顾莫琳
We moved to Missouri to save Maureen...
但是我们救不了她
but as it turns out, we couldn't.
你们过来的意义重大
It means a lot that you came.
我们赔钱卖掉豪宅
We took a hit on the brownstone...
我用最后一点信托基金买酒吧给他
and I used the last of my trust fund to buy him a bar.
目前为止都还在亏钱
So far, it's just costing money.
尼克只用我来泄欲
Nick uses me for sex when he wants.
除此之外，我简直不存在
Otherwise, I don't exist. Whoo!
我们今天去澳美客吃饭
We should go to Outback tonight.
太好了
That would be nice.
昨晚，我从绝望到可悲
Last night, I went from desperate to pathetic.
我变成了自己一点都不喜欢的人
I became someone I don't even like.
我以前会嘲笑的那种女人
The kind of woman I used to mock.
你太常出门了
You're out so much.
我知道  - 留在家里
I know. Stay home.
不行，我迟到了  - 那我可以去吗？
I can't, I'm already late. Then, can I come?
你讨厌那种事
You would hate it.
只是一群蠢高中朋友聚会
It's a bunch of my dorky high school friends.
做那个动作，别骗我
Do our code. No bullshit.
我以为我们不会是那种夫妻
I thought we weren't gonna be that couple.
好了，再见
Okay, bye.
我一直在想  - 什么？
Hey, I've been thinking. Yeah?
来点正面的东西
Something positive.
也许是时候了
Maybe it's time.
现在是最不适合的时候了
Now is literally the worst time.
这可以是我们的新开始
It would be a new start for us.
我也有留在这里的真正目的
And for me, I would have a real purpose here.
养小孩不是一种兴趣
A child is not a hobby.
不是兴趣
Not a hobby.
是启发
An inspiration.
我们四小时前就可以吵了，我迟到了
We could have had this fight four hours ago. I'm late.
我不知道这会变成争吵
I didn't know it was gonna be a fight.
你想成为用小孩拯救婚姻的夫妻吗？
You really wanna be the couple that has a baby to save their marriage?
拯救？
"Save"?
重开机，重新来过，点燃爱火之类的
Reboot, retool, rekindle, whatever!
你打算现在这样走出去？  - 对
And you're gonna walk out the door now? Yeah!
你他妈的胆小鬼
You're a fucking coward.
不，这段婚姻不能这样下去
No, it can't go on like this.
是吗？
Oh, really?
我不允许  - 不允许？
I won't. You won't?
你不允许？你还不满意吗？
You won't? Why, it's not good enough for you?
差得远了
It's not even close!
你这愚蠢的贱人
You stupid bitch!
让我吓到的不是他推我
What scared me wasn't that he'd pushed me.
是他有多想进一步伤害我
What scared me was how much he wanted to hurt me more.
我吓坏了，因为我终于了解
What scared me was that I'd finally realized...
我自己的丈夫让我感到恐惧
I am frightened of my own husband.
你要我呼叫后援吗？
You want me to call for backup?
不用，我会保护你
Nah, I'll protect you.
老天
Jesus.
他们应该把这地方烧掉
They ought to burn this place down.
看来有人打算这么做
Seems like folks are trying.
你真的觉得这有用？
You really think this is anything?
就算没用也要来了才能确定
Cross it off the list.
杰森
Hey, Jason.
什么事，隆妲？
What's up, Rhonda?
“致力于凡人皆生而…”
"...and dedicated to the proposition that all men..."
你看过这女的来这里吗？  - 干嘛？
Have you seen this girl around here? Why do you ask?
她失踪了
She was reported missing.
“…能否长久、坚持…”
"...and so dedicated, can long endure."
我记得她
Yeah. I remember her.
她来干嘛？买大麻还是毒品？
What did she want? Weed, pills?
她想买枪
She wanted a gun.
我告诉她我不干这个
I told her it's not my thing.
但我觉得难过，因为她看起来很绝望
I felt bad, though. She seemed really desperate.
她说她要一把小的才能随身携带
She said it needed to be small so she could keep it close.
你确定是她？
Are you sure this is her?
在这里看到这种女孩很难忘记
You don't forget a girl like that in here.
她穿着一身粉红色
She was all in pink.
而且那天是情人节
It was Valentine's Day.
“2012年2月14日”
2012-2-14
情人节到了，我应该买一把枪
For Valentine's Day, I thought I'd buy a gun.
我就是变得这么疯狂
That is how crazy I've become.
尼克要我消失，但他没说要离婚
Nick wants me gone but he won't ask for a divorce.
在他心里我是酒吧的老板
In his mind, I'm the owner of his bar,
唯一的出资方
his only line of credit.
提出婚前协议书的贱人
The bitch with the prenup.
我可以回去找我爸妈
I could go home to my parents...
但那样我就得把事实全盘托出
but I'd have to tell them the truth.
我甚至不知道自己相不相信事实
And I don't even know if I believe the truth.
我真的觉得尼克会伤害我吗？
Can I really think Nick would hurt me?
我有被害妄想吧，我疯了
I'm being paranoid. Crazy.
这根本…
It's just...
我有枪应该会睡得比较好
I'd sleep better with a gun.
“协寻爱咪”
“7月8日  事发之后三日”
该死
Oh, shit.
宝贝，醒醒，我妹要出来了
Wake up, baby. My sister's gonna come out here.
抱歉我得赶你  - 没关系
Sorry to rush you. It's okay.
我来帮你  - 好
Here. Let me help you.  Okay.
拿那个
Just get that.
你要很小心
Be very careful.
我没事
I'm all right.
好了
Here you go.
答应我你每天都会打给我
Promise me we'll talk every day.
会的
Okay, we will.
每天，尼克，不然我会疯掉
Every day, Nick, or I'll go crazy.
不要疯掉
Don't go crazy.
好
Okay-
你这该死的白痴
You fucking idiot.
他妈的混蛋，该死的当着我的面说谎
You fucking asshole! You fucking lied to my fucking face!
对不起
I'm sorry.
她几岁？
How old is she?
20出头
She's in her early 20s.
多久了？
How long?
一年半  - 你骗了我一年多？
A year and a half.  You lied to me for over a year?
如果我告诉你，你会阻止我
Oh, if I told you, you would have made me stop.
她是超他妈的嫩草
It's so fucking small.
你这个劈腿的骗子，跟爸没两样
You're a liar and a cheat! You're just like Dad!
你怎么认识她的？
How did you even meet her?
她是我的学生
She's one of my students.
我以为作家都讨厌老套
I thought writers hated cliches.
我不是作家
Oh, I'm not a writer.
“呜呜，我被裁员了，我要上个嫩妹”
"Oh, boo-hoo, I got laid off. I guess I'll fuck a teenager."
不是那样的，你不知道跟爱咪在一起
It wasn't like that, okay? You have no idea how shitty it was with Amy...
有多悲惨，她让我觉得自己他妈的糟
how fucking terrible she made me feel.
我就是个乡巴佬，每天光是回家
Flyover Boy. I would get knots in my stomach...
想到她坐在那儿，胃都要打结了
just coming home, knowing she would be sitting there...
我还没进门就知道她会抱怨连连
dissatisfied, before I even walked in the fucking door.
真是太糟了
This is so bad.
如果有人发现这事你就完蛋了
If anybody finds out, you're totally fucked.
邦妮在我办公室发现一条内裤
Boney found a pair of panties in my office...
偶尔我和安蒂会在那里…
where, occasionally, Andie and I...
我不知道那代表什么鬼
I don't know what the fuck it means.
是那个蠢货的吗？
Are they Super-Twat's?
她叫做安蒂
Her name is Andie.
她不确定
She's not entirely sure.
所以现在有个20岁的女生
So we are dealing with a 20-year-old...
不知道自己的内裤掉在哪里？
who isn't sure where she leaves her undies?
如果不是安蒂的，就是爱咪的
If they're not Andie's, that means that they're Amy's...
她放在那里让我去找
and she left them there for me to find.
尼克，我本来担心你，现在我吓坏了
Nick, I was scared for you before，and now, I'm fucking petrified.
今天晚上有巡逻队在找你失踪的妻子
We're having a vigil tonight for your missing wife...
今天早上你还跟你的大学小女友吻别
and this morning, you're kissing your college girlfriend goodbye!
你能想像吗？
Can you imagine?
你最近看过电视了吗？
Have you watched television lately?
新闻台都在报导你的八卦
Cable news is all over your shit.
这个酒吧老板怎么了？
I mean, what is wrong with this barkeep?
他老婆都还下落不明
His wife's nowhere to be found...
但是尼克却有空调情，照片可爱吧？
and here's Nick Dunne for you, flirting.  Cute pic, huh?
那是谁？  - 某个追着惨案跑的神经病
Who is that?  Some fucking tragedy groupie.
他妈的她是谁？  - 我不知道
Who the fuck is that? I don't know.
她说要做菜给我吃
She was trying to give me a casserole.
今天节目邀请到辩护律师坦纳波尔特
On the show today we have defense attorney, Tanner Bolt...
世界各地杀妻凶手心中的圣人
patron saint to wife-killers everywhere-
坦纳，你真的考虑帮尼克辩护吗？
Tanner Bolt, would you actually consider defending Nick Dunne?
这么说吧
Well, let me just say...
一如往常，谢谢你的介绍，艾伦
as always, Ellen, thank you for such a warm welcome.
当然我愿意为尼克邓恩辩护
But of course, I'd defend Nick Dunne.
听着，他只是没有哭哭啼啼
Listen, just because this guy isn't walking around weeping...
不代表他没有受伤
that doesn't mean that he's not hurting.
反社会分子的共通性就是毫无同情心
Tanner, the hallmark of a sociopath is a lack of empathy.
但你得先是个反社会分子
But the truth is, you'd have to be a sociopath...
才能在这种情况下保持正常
to behave normally in this situation...
因为这是世界上最不正常的情况了
because it's the most abnormal situation in the world.
坦纳，你是想告诉我这张照片
Tanner, are you trying to tell me that this photo...
还是属于可接受的行为的范围吗？
is remotely in the realm of acceptable behavior?
我真受够了被女人挑剔
I'm so sick of being picked apart by women.
你得雇用坦纳波尔特
You need to hire Tanner Bolt.
我不该被这样批评
I don't deserve this.
无罪推定原则
Innocent until proven guilty.
那正是你应得的
That's exactly what you deserve.
回家吧，尼克
Go home, Nick.
“协寻爱咪”
兄弟
Hey, buddy.
我不敢相信我们还没逮捕他
I can't believe we haven't arrested this guy.
我们不会因为一个金发笨蛋
We're not gonna arrest anybody...
就随便逮捕任何人
just because some blonde dunce says so.
为什么对他那么好？你爱上他了？
Why are you going so easy on him? You got a crush?
第一，我在进行调查，不是狩猎女巫
One, l am conducting an investigation, not a witch-hunt.
第二，不准再那样跟我说话
And, two, don't talk to me that way, ever.
她想买一把枪
She was trying to buy a gun.
我们不知道是谁让她害怕
We don't know who or what was scaring her, Gil.
告诉我最新的结果
Give me the update.
没有吸毒的情况，可以划掉这项了
No drug angles panned out yet, so cross that off the list.
我跟照顾尼克父亲的护士谈过
I talked to the nurses who care for Nick's father.
那个混帐现在很虚弱，这也可以排除
The guy's a bastard, but he's weak as a kitten, so cross that off the list.
你好  - 你好
- Hey. - Hey.
厨房的鲁米诺反应像7月4日的烟火
So, luminol lit up the kitchen like the 4th of July.
哇  - 没错
Whoa. Yeah.
血超多的
The blood is profuse.
是爱咪的B型血，DNA结果很快会出来
It is Amy's, type B, and we should have DNA soon.
凶器呢？
Thoughts on a weapon?
轨迹显示应该是钝物
Trajectory indicates blunt force.
可能是5乘10公分的棍子
Maybe a club or a two-by-four.
她倒在这里，但我怀疑她回头了
She fell there, but I doubt she got back up.
有爱咪的医疗纪录吗？
Amy's medical records come in?
还没，今天晚上会拿到
No, we'll have them later tonight.
我老婆说是他杀的
My wife says he's a killer.
如果你老婆说了算，那…
Well, if Tiffany says...
”酒吧” ”BAR”
你来了
Hey-
我来了
谢谢你们过来
Thank you all for coming out.
东尼，你好吗？
Hey Donnie, how are you?
瑞奇，谢谢你
Rich, thank you so much.
你们好
Hey. Hmm.
谢谢你们各位今天来到这里
Thank you, folks. Thank you for being here tonight.
这对我们家来说意义深远
It just means the world to our family.
对爱咪也是
And to Amy.
如各位所知
As you all know...
我妻子，爱咪艾略特邓恩
my wife, Amy Elliott Dunne...
三天前失踪了
disappeared three days ago.
我想呼吁所有人有任何消息
And I want to implore anyone who has any information at all...
都请和我们联络，帮助我们
please come forward. Help us.
他好帅
So hot.
他好变态
Ew! He is so creepy.
我想说，因为你们有些人可能在想
I wanna say something because I think some of you might be wondering...
但又不好意思开口问
and are too polite to ask.
但我和我妻子的失踪没有任何关系
I had nothing to do with the disappearance of my wife.
我正在和警方合作
I'm cooperating with the police.
我还没有聘请律师
I haven't hired a lawyer.
我没什么好隐瞒的
I have nothing to hide.
爱咪是我的灵魂伴侣
Amy is my soul mate.
她既聪明
She is brilliant...
又迷人，而且充满智慧
she's charming, and wise.
我爱你，爱咪
I love you, Amy.
混蛋
Asshole.
我爱我的妻子
I love my wife...
非常深
so much.
我在镜头前的表现也许不符合期待
And I may not behave for the cameras the way they want me to...
如果他们要因此惩罚我，也没关系
and if they wanna punish me for that, that's okay.
但我只想请媒体朋友，骚扰我就好
But I just wanna ask you in the media, please, harass me...
不要打扰这座镇上的大家
but don't harass the people of this town.
如果你们要嘲弄什么人，嘲弄我
If you need to mock somebody, mock me.
尼克
Nick!
但是不要把调查搞成马戏团
But please don't turn this investigation into a circus.
你的妻子在哪里，尼克？
Where's your wife, Nick?
让警方好好工作
Let the police do their jobs.
你对你怀孕的妻子做了什么？
What did you do to your pregnant wife?
你告诉他们了吗，尼克？
Did you tell them that, Nick?
你告诉他们爱咪怀孕六周了吗？
Did you tell them Amy was six weeks pregnant?
谢谢各位的支持，让我们找到爱咪
Thank you for your support tonight. Let's find Amy.
如果你们想发言，请便
Go ahead, if you guys wanna say something.
吉尔宾，上
Gil, go, go.
尼克，你要去哪里？
Nick, where are you going?
阻止他
Stop him!
请不要提问了，谢谢
No questions right now. Thank you.
你为什么要跑？
Why are you running away?
不要跑
Don't run.
所有人退后
Everybody, stay back.
各位，你们应该知道怎么做
Guys, come on. You know better.
从草丛里出来，到路边来
Get off the grass, get down to the curb.
吉尔宾  - 我知道
- Hey, Gil... - On it.
好吧
All right.
你们都听到了，不准拍照
All right, y'all heard her. No pictures.
是谁？
Hello?
谁？
妈的
Fuck.
你吓到我了，要喝东西吗？
You scared me. Want a drink?
你知道她怀孕了吗？
Did you know she was pregnant?
我告诉过你诺耶儿是他妈的疯子
I told you, Noelle Hawthorne is fucking crazy.
她根本不认识爱咪
She doesn't even know Amy.
我倒觉得她们是好朋友
They look like pretty good friends to me.
我不知道，但这也不能证明她怀孕了
Look, I don't know. But it certainly doesn't prove that she's pregnant.
她医疗记录快送来了
We have her medical records coming.
很好  - 我们边等边聊吧
Good. So, let's talk while we wait.
从这边开始好了，犯罪现场
Let's start over here. The scene of the crime.
我们看过很多入侵住宅的案子
You see, we've seen dozens of home invasions.
好几十个
Dozens and dozens.
这个地方我们一看就觉得有问题
This area right here, it looked wrong from the second we saw it.
整个场景就像是刻意安排的，你看
The whole thing looked staged. Watch this.
爱咪在生死关头挣扎，但相框都没事？
And yet, they remained upright throughout this life-and-death struggle?
我不知道，你想要我说什么？
I don't know. What do you want me to say?
你太太失踪那天你有打扫家里吗？
Did you do any housekeeping the day your wife went missing?
没有
No.
因为我们的人做了鲁米诺测试
Because our guys did a luminol test.
很抱歉，不过厨房有血迹反应
And I'm sorry to tell you, but that kitchen lit up.
爱咪在那里流了很多血，很多，尼克
Amy lost a lot of blood in there, Nick. A lot.
老天
Oh, my God.
对，有人擦过了
Yeah, and then somebody mopped it up.
等等，为什么他们要把血擦掉
Oh... Wait a second. Why would they mop up the blood...
却又布置另一个犯罪场景？
if they're trying to stage a crime scene?
没有血迹和尸体，会让人想到绑架
No blood and no body suggests kidnapping.
看起来像是外人做的
It tells us, look at people outside the house.
像你一直提到的那些游民
Like these homeless you keep mentioning.
很多血迹但没有尸体，就会像谋杀
A pool of blood and no body suggests homicide.
我们就会调查家里的人
It tells us to look at people inside the house.
也就是我们现在的方向  - 我懂了
Which is what we're doing here, Nick.  I see.
你的婚姻如何？现在只有诺耶儿的说法
So, how was your marriage, Nick? Because right now, all we got is Noelle.
她说“不好”
She says, "Not good."
吉尔宾，你跟你太太都吵什么？
Gil, what do you and your wife argue about?
什么会惹火你？  - 钱，缺钱的事
What pisses you off? Oh, money, lack thereof.
我和我前夫也是一样
Me and my ex, it's the same.
我这么说是因为我们看了你的财务
I mention that because we got a look at your finances, Nick.
你欠了11万7千的卡债
$117,000 in credit card debt.
什么？  - 我调出了一些商品资料
What? I pulled up some of the merchandise.
都是些好玩的小奢侈品
There are these fun little splurges.
我没买过这些东西
I didn't buy any of this stuff.
我根本不打高尔夫
I don't even golf!
我会打，你买的球杆很棒
I do! You bought great clubs.
我喜欢机器狗
I like the robot dog.
我被盗刷了，这是诈骗
This is identity theft! This is a felony!
我们要找出谁做了这事
We need to find out who did this!
好，我们来谈谈寿险
All right. Let's talk about life insurance.
你在四月时突然提高爱咪的保额
Because in April, you bumped up Amy's life insurance...
现在是120万美元
to $1.2 million.
对，是她提议的，她要我这么做
Yes, I did. That was her idea. She wanted me to.
你寄出了文件
You filed the paperwork.
因为她叫我寄
Because she told me to! Whoa!
等一下
Hold on a sec.
怎样？好
Yeah? Okay.
确定吗？
For sure?
好
All right.
她确实怀孕了
She was pregnant.
这太离谱了
This is insane.
我的问题变成…
So, my question becomes...
我不愿意再和你们交谈
I don't want to talk to you again, ever...
除非有律师在场
without a lawyer.
玛戈
Margo!
小猫
Hey-
等等，让我把这弄完
Just hold on a second. Let me finish.
尼克
Nick?
我听到了，我也很惊讶
I hear you, I hear you. I was as surprised as...
我知道你很生气，我不知道她怀孕了
I know you're upset. I had no idea she was pregnant.
听着，我也这么以为，但显然不是
Listen, I thought so, too, but evidently that wasn't...
你想知道事实？
You want to know the truth?
事实是爱咪不想要小孩
The truth is, Amy didn't want kids.
我也一样惊讶
Well, I'm as surprised as...
你跟我说是你不想要小孩
You told me you didn't want kids.
我试着扮演好人
I was trying to put a good face on.
突然间你有个怀孕的妻子
Then, suddenly, you've got a pregnant wife.
这对你来说是个问题
That's a problem for you.
更别忘了你还有个秘密小女友
Especially when you factor in the secret teenage girlfriend.
别再看艾伦亚波特的节目了
Oh, stop watching Ellen Abbott!
你他妈的好好跟我谈一谈
You have to fucking talk to me!
她要我别告诉你是她不想要小孩
I didn't tell you that she didn't want kids because she didn't want me to.
因为你会因此更讨厌她
Because it would have just been another reason for you to hate her.
我们已经受够了，所以干脆…
And we had enough of those already! It was easier to just...
骗我？  - 我想要小孩的
Lie to me? I wanted kids!
我们一搬来就去过妇产科了
When we first moved here, I went to a fertility clinic!
没有用吗？  - 我该做的都做了
It didn't work? I did my part!
打手枪
Masturbate.
结果轮到爱咪的时候，她突然说
When it came time for Amy to do her thing, all of a sudden it was like...
“我不知道，还是不要吧，谢谢”
"Well, I don't know. Maybe. No, thanks."
现在谁会相信你？
Now, who would believe you?
好吧
All right.
这是诊所寄来的信
This is a letter from the clinic...
通知我，如果我不联络他们
notifying me that they're gonna destroy my sample...
他们就会销毁我的样本
unless I contact them.
所以我拿给爱咪看
So, I gave it to Amy.
隔天就在垃圾桶里看见这封信
The next day, I saw it in the trash.
你那时候已经跟安蒂在一起了吧？
But you were already with Andie by then, right?
我本来是想和爱咪生孩子的
I wanted a baby with Amy.
一年前，爱咪如果怀孕是最棒的事了
A year ago, Amy being pregnant would have been the best thing ever!
“你可怜的爱咪一感冒，餐馆…”
"When your poor Amy has a cold, this dessert just..."
这是你没解开的线索
This is the clue you couldn't solve.
对
Yeah.
戴西寄来的，爱咪的恐怖男友？
A letter from Desi.That creepy boyfriend of Amy's?
这家伙他妈的有钱，什么都愿意做
It was the fucking rich guy who would do anything for her.
这件事一直挥之不去，让我反胃
It just kept hanging over my head. It was disgusting.
婚前协议书？
Your prenup?
你为何要留下这些文件？
Nick, why have you kept this stuff?
我不知道，可能我恨她吧
It's like a little box of hate. I don't know, Go! Maybe I hate her!
不管怎么样我都爱你
I love you no matter what.
但你要告诉我
But you need to tell me.
告诉你什么？
Tell you what?
你在问我什么？
What are you asking me?
你是在问我有没有杀了我老婆吗？
Are you asking me if I killed my wife, Go?
你在问我这个吗？我有没有杀我老婆？
Is that what you're asking me? If I murdered my wife?
我绝对不会问你这个
I would never ask you that!
玛戈
Margo!
不要踩到玻璃
Don't walk on the glass.
你没有线索吧？
Oh.You have no clue, do you?
“线索三”
为什么他那天晚上会在这里？
Why was he here that night?
他太太失踪了，为什么要来这里？
His wife is missing. Why come here?
谁在乎呢？
Who cares?
隆妲，我们知道了
Rhonda, we got this.
就逮捕他吧
Let's make the arrest.
你知道没有尸体，谋杀罪多难起诉吗？
Do you know how hard it is to make a murder case without a body?
不知道
No.
告诉你，超级难
Well, it's incredibly hard.
所以我需要最后一样东西
So, I want one last thing.
什么？
What's that?
我需要尸体
I want a body.
想像我是个坏透了的女孩
Picture me, I'm a girl who's very, very bad.
小心点
Be careful.
你要惩罚我，要对我使坏
I need to be punished, and by "punished,"
“坏-惩罚  鞭子  锁链  奴隶”
I mean "had."
妈的
Fuck.
你把五周年的好东西都藏在这儿
It's where you keep goodies for anniversary five.
那就打开门…
So, open the door...
惩罚，木头，沙滩
Punish. Wood. Beach.
仔细瞧瞧这儿
...and look alive.
惩罚，木头
Punish. Wood.
木头
Wood.
我会试着相信我丈夫依然爱我
I will practice believing my husband loves me...
也会爱这个宝宝
and will love this baby.
这个孩子也许真的能拯救我们的婚姻
That this child might really save our marriage.
但我也可能错了
But I could be wrong.
因为有时候
Because sometimes...
他看着我的样子
the way he looks at me...
让我觉得
I think...
我的梦中情人
man of my dreams...
我孩子的父亲
father of my child...
我的男人，他可能会杀了我
this man of mine may kill me.
他可能真的会
He may truly...
杀了我
kill me.
搞什么鬼？
WTF?
此刻我已经是死人，太开心了
I am so much happier now that I'm dead.
“7月5日  事发当日”
技术上来说，“我失踪了”
Technically, "missing."
并且即将被推定已经死亡
Soon to be presumed dead.
“2012年7月5日  杀了爱咪”
我走了
Gone.
而我那个懒惰，说谎，劈腿
And my lazy, lying, cheating,
健忘的老公
oblivious husband...
会因为谋杀我而入狱
will go to prison for my murder.
尼克邓恩夺走我的骄傲与尊严
Nick Dunne took my pride and my dignity...
我的希望和我的钱
and my hope and my money.
他对我予取予求，直到我不再存在
He took and took from me until I no longer existed.
这就是谋杀
That's murder.
让他罪有应得
Let the punishment fit the crime.
安排一场有说服力的谋杀需要自律
To fake a convincing murder, you have to have discipline.
你要和当地的某个蠢货当好朋友
You befriend a local idiot.
从她无聊的生活里收集细节
Harvest the details of her humdrum life.
说些你老公的坏脾气的故事骗她
And cram her with stories about your husband's violent temper.
偷偷制造一些金钱问题
Secretly create some money troubles.
信用卡或是线上赌博
Credit cards, perhaps online gambling.
搞不清楚情况的人
With the help of the unwitting...
还会帮忙你提高寿险金额
bump up your life insurance.
在二手网站买一辆逃跑用的车
Purchase getaway car. Craigslist.
要普通，便宜，并且现金交易
Generic. Cheap. Pay cash.
需要包装，大家才会惋惜你的离去
You need to package yourself so that people will truly mourn your loss.
美国人最爱怀孕妇女了
And America loves pregnant women.
彷佛你是贞洁烈女
As if it's so hard to spread your legs.
你知道最难的是什么吗？
You know what's hard?
假装怀孕
Faking a pregnancy.
首先你要把马桶的水抽干
First, drain your toilet.
邀请怀孕的白痴来你家
Invite pregnant idiot into your home...
让她一直喝柠檬水
and ply her with lemonade.
把怀孕的白痴的尿液偷走
Steal pregnant idiot's urine.
成功
Voilà.
现在你的合法医疗记录里就有怀孕了
A pregnancy is now part of your legal medical record.
纪念日快乐
Happy anniversary.
等你毫不知情的丈夫
Wait for your clueless husband...
开始他的一天
to start his day.
当他出门以后
Off he goes.
倒数计时开始
And the clock is ticking.
你要精心布置犯罪现场
Meticulously stage your crime scene...
留下足以让人起疑的错误
with just enough mistakes to raise the specter of doubt.
你得流血
You need to bleed.
很多血
A lot.
很多很多
A lot, a lot.
像是头受伤流的血那么多
A head wound kind of bleed.
犯罪现场需要的血量
A crime scene kind of bleed.
你还要笨手笨脚地清理
You need to clean poorly...
就像他那样
like he would.
清理，再流血，清理，再流血
Clean and bleed. Bleed and clean.
最后留下不该留下的东西
And leave a little something behind.
在七月生火？
A fire in July?
因为你是你
And because you're you...
所以你不会只做到这样
you don't stop there.
你需要一本日记
You need a diary.
最少要三百篇，写尼克和爱咪的故事
Minimum, 300 entries on the Nick and Amy story.
从童话故事般美好的早期写起
Start with the fairy tale early days.
那些是真的，而且至关重要
Those are true. And they're crucial.
你总要让尼克和爱咪讨人喜欢
You want Nick and Amy to be likeable.
接着就开始自由发挥了
After that, you in vent.
花钱如流水
The spending.
虐待，恐惧
The abuse. The fear.
暴力威胁
The threat of violence.
尼克以为自己才是作家
And Nick thought he was the writer.
烧掉的分量要刚刚好
Burn it just the right amount.
确保警察会找到这本日记
Make sure the cops will find it.
“线索三”
最后特别以寻宝游戏向过去致敬
Finally, honor tradition with a very special treasure hunt.
“7月5日  事发之后两小时”
如果我都做对了，全世界都会恨尼克
And if I get everything right, the world will hate Nick...
因为他杀了美丽又怀孕的妻子
for killing his beautiful, pregnant wife.
在群情激愤之下，等我准备好
And after all the outrage, when I'm ready...
我会带着很多药九，搭船出去
I'll go out on the water with a handful of pills...
口袋里装满石头
and a pocket full of stones.
等他们找到我的尸体时就会知道
And when they find my body, they'll know...
尼克邓恩把他亲爱的老婆当垃圾丢了
Nick Dunne dumped his beloved like garbage.
她载浮载沉，漂过其他同样…
And she floated down past all the other...
受虐，被遗弃，没用的女人身边
abused, unwanted, inconvenient women.
然后尼克也难逃一死
Then, Nick will die, too.
尼克和爱咪会离开人间
Nick and Amy will be gone.
但其实我们也不曾真正存在
But, then, we never really existed.
尼克爱的是我装出来的女孩
Nick loved a girl I was pretending to be.
“酷女郎”
"Cool Girl."
男人始终把这句话当作终极赞美
Men always use that as their defining compliment.
“她是个酷女郎”
"She's a cool girl."
“酷女郎好辣”
Cool Girl is hot.
“酷女郎什么都接受”
Cool Girl is game.
“酷女郎很风趣”
Cool Girl is fun.
酷女郎永远不对男人生气
Cool Girl never gets angry at her man.
她只会懊恼又惹人怜爱地微笑
She only smiles in a chagrined, loving manner...
然后帮她老公口交
and then presents her mouth for fucking.
她喜欢他喜欢的一切
She likes what he likes.
喜欢变态漫画和黑胶唱片
So evidently, he's a vinyl hipster who loves fetish manga.
他爱A片，她就是购物中心土妹
If he likes Girls Gone Wild, she's a mall babe...
会聊橄榄球，忍受波霸餐厅鸡翅
who talks football and endures buffalo wings at Hooters.
我遇见尼克时，就知道他想要酷女郎
When I met Nick Dunne, I knew he wanted Cool Girl.
我承认我愿意为他试试看
And for him, I'll admit, I was willing to try.
我帮我的阴部除毛
I wax-stripped my pussy raw.
我喝罐装啤酒，看亚当山德勒的电影
I drank canned beer watching Adam Sandier movies.
我吃冷掉的彼萨，还保持2号的身材
I ate cold pizza and remained a size two.
我三不五时帮他吹萧
I blew him semi-regularly.
我活在当下
I lived in the moment.
我他妈的什么都可以
I was fucking game.
我承认有些时候还满有趣的
I can't say I didn't enjoy some of it.
尼克解放了我不自觉的那一面
Nick teased out of me things I didn't know existed.
轻松，幽默，自在的一面
A lightness, a humor, an ease.
但我让他更聪明，更犀利
But I made him smarter. Sharper.
我启发他，让他达到我的层次
I inspired him to rise to my level.
我塑造我的梦中情人
I forged the man of my dreams.
“7月5日  事发之后十小时”
我们曾经因为假装自己而开心过
We were happy pretending to be other people.
我们曾经是全世界最快乐的一对
We were the happiest couple we knew.
如果不是最快乐的，干嘛在一起？
And what's the point of being together if you're not the happiest?
但尼克变懒了
But Nick got lazy.
他变成我不想嫁的那种人
He became someone I did not agree to marry.
他真的期望我可以无条件地爱他
He actually expected me to love him unconditionally.
接着他身无分文地把我拖到这鬼地方
Then he dragged me, penniless, to the navel of this great country...
还找到胸部又新又年轻，充满弹性的…
and found himself a newer, younger, bouncier...
酷女郎
Cool Girl.
你以为我会让他毁了我，自己快活吗？
You think I'd let him destroy me and end up happier than ever?
他妈的想都别想
No fucking way.
他不会赢的
He doesn't get to win.
我可爱，迷人，纯朴的密苏里男孩
My cute, charming, salt-of-the-earth, Missouri guy.
他得学个教训
He needed to learn.
大人为了想要的东西会努力
Grown-ups work for things.
大人会付出代价
Grown-ups pay-
大人要承受后果
Grown-ups suffer consequences.
等等
Wait.
给我20秒，不要批评我或打断我
I need 20 seconds where you don't judge me, interrupt me...
也不要生气
or get angry.
好
Okay-
这是信用卡上所有的东西吗？
Is that all the stuff from the credit cards?
“你把五周年的好东西都藏在哪儿？”
Where do you store goodies for anniversary five?
木头
Wood.
木棚  - 对，我的木棚
Woodshed.  Yeah, my woodshed.
妈的那个贱人
That fucking bitch.
我以为…  - 没关系
I thought... It's all right.
我也会这样
I would have, too.
那礼物是什么？
What's that present?
我不知道
I don't know.
我们看看
Let's find out.
“亲爱的老公，我知道你自认行动隐密
"Dear Husband,I know you think you're moving through this world unseen."
但你别傻了
"Don't believe that for a second.
我知道你去过哪里，要去哪里
"I know where you've been, and I know where you're going."
今年纪念日我为你安排一趟旅行
"For this anniversary, I've arranged a trip.
请随着你心爱的大河，逆流而上
"Follow the river, up, up, up.
请你放轻松，因为你已经完蛋了”
"Sit back and relax, because you are done."
什么是“逆流而上”
What's "up, up river"?
是“吃牢饭”的意思
"Up the river." Prison.
这贱人真是他妈的疯了
Fucking crazy bitch.
就是这么回事
That's what this is.
她设计我谋杀她
She's framing me for her murder.
你娶的是个彻头彻尾的神经病
You married a complete psychopath.
我们结婚纪念日早上
The morning of our anniversary...
我本来要跟她离婚，我受不了了
I was gonna ask her for a divorce. I just couldn't do it.
我再也撑不了一年甚至一天
I couldn't fake it for another year, another day.
结果怎么了？
Then what happened?
在我开口之前，她说
Before I could say anything, she said...
“我要你出门去，好好想想我们的婚姻”
"I need you to go somewhere and really think about our marriage."
她知道我会去索耶沙滩
She knew I would go to Sawyer Beach.
所以你没有不在场证明
So you'd have no alibi.
她设计我
She stage-managed me.
她知道我会做什么，我也都做了
She knew exactly what I would do. And I fucking did it.
我去了沙滩，思考我们的婚姻
I went to the beach, I thought about our marriage.
我回来后决定我要离婚
I came back and decided I wanted a divorce.
结果你一到家
And by the time you got home...
她就不见了
She was gone.
他妈的
Oh, you fuck!
她很厉害
She's good.
其实她不见的时候
Part of me was relieved...
有一部分的我松了一口气
when I thought she was gone.
是潘趣和茱迪的木偶
Punch and Judy puppets.
我记得他把茱迪打死，杀了宝宝
Remember, he beats Judy to death and kills that baby.
所以我是潘趣
So I'm Punch.
我们懂了，爱咪，你为什么要这样？
We already knew that, Amy, what's your point?
密苏里州有死刑吗？
Does Missouri have the death penalty?
“7月6日  事发之后一日”
“2012年12月  杀了自己？”
“11月  杀了自己？”
“丢弃车子  杀了自己？”
“研究弃车地点”
邻居你好
Hey, neighbor.
好几个礼拜我隔壁都没个像样的人了
It's been weeks since I had anyone decent next door.
我不知道我有多像样
Well, I don't know how decent I feel.
只要你没养蟒蛇
Well, as long as you don't own a python...
或半夜放黑死金就好
and blast death metal at 4 AM...
我们会是好朋友的
we're gonna be best friends.
好吧，很高兴认识你
All right. Nice meeting you.
我是葛芮妲
I'm Greta.
我是南西
I'm Nancy.
你要去商店吗？帮我买人造奶油
Are you going to the marina? I could use some creamer.
抱歉，没办法
Oh, I'm sorry. I can't.
我有事要做
I've got work to do.
好吧，回头见
All right. See you around!
肯定会的
You Will.
“7月7日  事发之后二日”
“艾伦亚波特”
让我瞧瞧可爱的尼克式微笑吧
Come on. Show me that darling Nicky smile.
你这混蛋
You asshole.
“协寻专线”
“7月8日  事发之后三日”
你好
Hey-
南西
Nancy.
今天又热昏了
It's hot again today.
你从哪里来的？
So, uh, where are you from?
我猜猜看
Let me guess.
内布拉斯加
Nebraska.
纽奥良
New Orleans.
我是涂防晒油专家
You know, l am an expert oiler.
我相信你是
Oh, I just bet you are.
不管是乳液，油膏或是软膏都行
Lotions and balms. Ointment.
我可不想看你们有晒痕
I would hate for y'all to get tan lines.
真贴心
So sweet.
好吧，你知道到哪里找我
Okay. You know where I'll be.
我们都不太会看男人
I see we have the same taste in men.
我是撞到浴室的柜子
I clipped it on a bathroom cabinet.
你根本没必要帮他隐瞒
Least you could do is not keep his secrets for him.
我猜猜看
Let me guess.
他想看重要比赛但你就是不闭嘴
He's trying to watch the big game and you just won't shut up.
不，你看起来不太爱讲话
No, you don't seem like much of a talker.
我知道了
Oh, I got it.
你抓到你男人跟某个骚货乱搞
You caught your boy rubbing up on some hot little skank...
他揍了你一拳当作道歉
and he apologized to you by busting you a good one.
更糟
Worse.
更糟？
Worse?
我去他工作的酒吧想给他惊喜
I went to the bar where he works to surprise him.
他和这个与酒吧无关的女孩走出来
And out he comes with this girl who had no business being in a bar.
我们刚认识的那天晚上
On the very first night that we met...
我们路过一间正在进货的糕饼店
we walked by a bakery that was having their sugar delivered.
空气里都是糖粉
And it was in the air, everywhere.
是一场糖粉风暴
A sugar storm.
在他亲吻我之前
And before he kissed me...
他倾身
he leaned in...
这么做
and did this.
结果你猜怎么样  - 怎么样？
And guess what. What?
他对那个女孩做了一样的事
He did the exact same thing with her.
这是我听过最恶心的事了
That is the most disgusting thing I ever heard.
谢谢你
Thank you.
喔~
Wow.
非常谢谢你
Thanks very much.
“中部谜案”
我们上全国新闻了
Well, we've gone mainstream.
“7月9日  事发之后四日”
这是上诉程序，我们会向他们上诉
It's an appeals process, so we will attempt to appeal to them.
波尔特先生吗？是坦纳波尔特吗？
Mr. Bolt. Tanner Bolt?
尼克邓恩
Nick Dunne.
我一直在等你打电话给我，朋友
I have been sitting by the phone, my friend.
很抱歉
I'm sorry.
你不相信我吗？
Do you not believe me?
我相信，但这是我听过最荒谬的事了
No, I believe you. It's just the craziest thing I've ever heard.
我很喜欢这故事，但你也太惨了
I love it. But, for you, it sucks.
不过这时候你不得不佩服你老婆吧
But you gotta have a grudging respect for your wife at this point, right?
你是在嘲笑我没希望吗？  - 不是
Are you laughing me out of the building?  No!
你开玩笑吗？我要接
Are you kidding me? I'm in.
我绝对要接这个案子
I'm way in.
你找对人了，我是专家，尼克
You came to the right guy. This is what I do, Nick.
所以我收10万，我专赢不可能的案子
This is why I have a $100,000 retainer. I win the unwinnable cases.
10万？
$100,000?
我们会想办法的
We'll figure something out.
让我帮你打个折
I'll give you a special...
“我老婆为了报复而死”的优惠价
"my wife is skilled in the art of vengeance" rate.
好
Okay-
你有什么打算？
So, what's the plan?
现在都还在各说各话的阶段
Well, right now, it's a "he said, she said."
她的故事比较迷人  - 不，尼克
She's telling a better story.  No, Nick.
她说的故事很完美
She is telling the perfect story.
所以我们必须从今天开始就准备你的抗辩，以防万一。
So, we need to start today to prepare your defense, should we need it.
万一需要时，如果是你的版本  - 真相
And if we decide to go with your version of... The truth.
我们就需要改变大众对爱咪的观感
Then we'll need to realign the public's perception of Amy.
让他们不再认为她是美国甜心
Make them stop seeing her as America's sweetheart...
揭开她操弄人心的真面目
and see her for what she is ，which a mind-fucker of the first degree.
这可不容易，我们需要其他人的佐证
Now, that is a huge realignment.We'll need other voices besides yours.
她过去一定也搞过别人
There has to be someone out there that she's screwed with in the past.
在纽约有一个叫汤米欧哈拉的家伙
There's a New York guy. O'Hara, Tommy O'Hara.
八年前她控告过他
Eight years ago she pressed charges against him.
那应该很好找
That should be easy to find.
还有她以前的同学戴西柯林斯
Um, ex-classmate, Desi Collings.
她说他跟踪她，他住在圣路易斯
She said that he stalked her. He's in St. Louis.
你要和汤米谈谈，我来拟合约
You go talk to Tommy, and I'll draw up the contract.
我告诉过你，你找我就对了
I told you, you came to the right guy.
显然是
Apparently.
是汤米吗？
Tommy?
我是
Yeah.
谢谢你愿意见我  - 别废话了
Thanks for seeing me. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
你会想喝杯酒的
Urn, you're gonna want a drink.
对
Yeah.
她说你对她动手动脚
So, she said you got physical with her.
不，老兄，她说我强暴她
No, dude, she said I raped her.
第一级的强暴重罪
First degree, felony rape.
你有吗？  - 你有吗？
Did you do it? Did you do it?
刑期是30年到终身监禁
Yeah.I was looking at 30 years to life.
你有被审判吗？  - 他妈的没有
Did you get a trial? Fuck, no.
我看起来是能热过苦牢的人吗？
Do I look like I would do well in the yard?
我认罪减轻罪名，一级性侵不用入狱
I pled down, man. Sexual assault one, no jail time.
差真多  - 是啊
That's something. Oh, yeah.
我过去八年都找不到工作
I've been unemployed for the last eight years...
因为我必须在求职履历写上“性侵犯”
because I have to write "sexual offender" on every job application.
我还在通报名单上，注记为性侵犯
I'm on a neighborhood watch list because I have to register as a predator.
我大概十年没有约会了，只要上网查…
I haven't had a date in almost a decade because if a girl googles me...
你可以告诉我来龙去脉吗？
Could you walk me through what happened?
我在一个派对上认识爱咪
I meet Amy at this party, you know?
我们一拍即合，她完美极了
We click. She's perfect.
又漂亮又聪明，书读得也多
She's beautiful, she's smart, she's well-read...
她的屁股像20岁的脱衣舞娘一样
she's got an ass like a 20-year-old stripper.
我心想，一定有问题
I think, "What's the catch?"
几个月后我懂了，跟她交往可不容易
A few months, it hits me. This is not going to be easy.
女人都喜欢改造男人，但爱咪呢？
Girls like a fixer-upper, but Amy?
她要控制我，把我变成她的
She annexed me. She made me her business.
这样太过分了，她会出门帮我买领带
It was just too much. She went out and bought me ties.
我们总要为此吵上20次
And we must have gone 20 rounds over that.
领带，还有所有一切都…
Ties. The whole thing just became...
所以你跟她分手  - 没有，我只是退缩
So, you broke up with her.  No, I just backed away.
给她一点空间，不算什么吧？
Gave her some space. No big deal, right?
我是这么想的
So I thought.
结果有天晚上爱咪来我家
Then one night, Amy comes over to my place...
带着一瓶波本酒和我喜欢的乐团CD
with a bottle of bourbon and a bootleg of this band I love.
两分钟之内她就脱了我的裤子
And within two minutes, she's got my pants around my ankles...
她跪下来，然后…
and she is kneeling down, and...
抱歉，我知道她是你太太
I'm sorry. I know it's your wife.
你们做了？  - 没错，两相情愿的性关系
You had sex? Yeah, consensual.
很粗暴，但是她想要的
It was rough, but she was screaming for it.
隔天早上两个警察就来敲门了
Next morning, there's two cops at my door.
爱咪身上有多处伤口和暴力性侵吻合
Amy has wounds that are consistent with rape.
手腕上有勒痕和我的精液
Ligature marks on her wrist, and my semen.
看起来就像我绑住爱咪然后强暴她
It looks like I've tied Amy to my bed, and raped her.
我G
Me!
后来你猜他们发现什么了
And then, guess what they find.
在我的床头板两侧靠床垫处有两条…
Headboards of my bed, one on each side.
你不愿意戴的那些领带
The ties you wouldn't wear.
你真了解你太太
You do know your wife.
你后来有见再过她吗？  - 有啊
Did you ever see her again? Yeah.
在电视上，上礼拜跟你在一起
On TV, last week, with you.
我心想，“那就是爱咪
I thought, "There's Amy.
她已经从遭强暴晋级到被谋杀了”
"She's graduated from being raped to being murdered."
“暴力  犯罪”
Mmm!
你也在看这个？
You been watching this, too?
昨天晚上惊爆内幕
Last night's bombshell.
我们刚发现
We just found out...
爱咪艾略特邓恩在失踪时已经怀孕
Amy Elliott Dunne was, indeed, pregnant when she went missing.
凯莉卡普托诺，这让我都想吐了
Kelly Capitono, this makes me wanna throw up.
怀孕，身体里有一个生命的女性
What is it about a pregnant woman...a  woman carrying life inside her...
怎么会让男人变成禽兽呢？
that turns men into animals?
艾伦，这是很普遍的现象
Ellen, this is an epidemic.
怀孕女性的第三大死因
The third leading cause of death among pregnant women...
就是遭到男友或丈夫的杀害
is homicide committed by a boyfriend or husband.
我们千万别忘了失踪的妻子
Let's not forget about the wife, ever.
今天我们请到爱咪的好友诺耶儿霍桑
Tonight, we welcome Amy's best friend, Noelle Hawthorne.
谢谢你来上节目，诺耶儿
Thanks for being on the show, Noelle.
谢谢你，艾伦
Thank you, Ellen.
我这么说吧
And let me just say this...
爱咪一定很爱你及你为女性做的一切
Amy would have loved you, and all you do for women.
那真好
Oh, that's nice.
跟我们谈谈你朋友吧，诺耶儿
Why don't you tell us about your friend, Noelle?
爱咪很有爱心
Amy was so nurturing.
我真希望有天听到有人说
Oh, I'd love if just once, someone was like...
“她超爱抱怨的”
"She was a real rag."
她美丽，聪明又温柔
She was beautiful and smart and kind.
我觉得她就像个有钱的贱女人
Seems like a rich bitch to me.
什么意思？大家都爱她
What do you mean? People love her.
我不知道，她看起来很自大
I don't know. She seems uppity.
被宠坏的千金小姐，嫁给劈腿的混蛋
Spoiled rich girl, married a cheating asshole.
付出了最大的代价
Paid the ultimate price.
唯一的秘密是她丈夫，我没见过尼克
The only secret was her husband.We never met Nick.
他从不自我介绍
He never introduced himself.
你觉得为什么会这样呢，诺耶儿？
Why was that, Noelle? Why do you think?
我想我们都知道为什么
I think we know why.
因为他有暴力倾向
Because he had a violent temper.
你有点严苛
A little harsh.
这就是人生，宝贝
That's life, baby.
他知道我可以看透他
He knew I'd have seen right through him.
别误会我了
Don't get me wrong.
我不认为他可以杀掉她
I'm not saying it's okay he killed her.
我只是说事出必有因
I'm just saying, there are consequences.
真他妈的好喝
Fuck, yeah.
她很孤单
She was so alone.
她也很无辜
And she was so innocent.
你是个好朋友，也是本节目之友
You're a good friend, Noelle. And you're a good friend of the show.
谢谢你来
Thanks for coming on.
告诉我你搞定坦纳波尔特了
Please tell me you landed Tanner Bolt.
坦纳波尔特搞定我了
Tanner Bolt landed me.
我回程会试着去找戴西柯林斯
I'm gonna try and see Desi Collings on my way home.
还有，小戈
And, Go...
坦纳要收10万美元
Tanner's retainer is $100,000.
而且只是订金
That's just the retainer.
我的存款有四万七，退休金有两千五
Listen, I've got $47,000 in savings. I've got $2,500 in an IRA.
房子可以办二次贷款，可以凑到的
I'm approved for a second mortgage on the house. We will go from there.
谢谢你
Thank you.
我爱你  - 我也爱你
I love you. I love you, too.
尼克把阿兹海默症的父亲送到养老院
Nick keeps his father, who has Alzheimer's, in a facility.
去年他去看过他几次？一次
Number of times he visited last year? One.
妈的
Oh, fuck!
他的双胞胎妹妹玛戈也很贴心
His twin sister, Margo, well, she is a peach.
两人整天都泡在爱咪买的酒吧里
These two spend their days in the bar Amy bought them.
玩什么？扮家家酒吗？
Playing what, Lauren? Playing house?
说什么鬼话
What the fuck?
双胞胎经常会互相掩饰
Twin siblings often enable and abet.
虽然我没有诊断过尼克和他妹妹
While I never examined Nick, or his sister...
但他们似乎非常亲密
they both seem very, very close.
双胞胎乱伦
It's twin-cest.
亲密得让人不舒服，萝伦
Disturbingly close, Lauren.
最后我们用一个问题结尾
And so, we close with a question.
是什么样丧心病狂的人
What kind of moral rot...
会让一个美丽，有才华
allows a beautiful, talented, kind, smart,
温柔，聪明的母亲
loving mother...
在叫天天不应的情况下消失呢？
to vanish without the heavens hearing our outraged cries?
可以借根烟吗？
Can I bum a cigarette? Yeah.
爱咪，我们关心你，会记得你
Amy Elliott Dunne, we care about you, and we will not forget.
我们还会记得什么？
And you know what else we won't forget?
密苏里州有死刑
Missouri has the death penalty.
阿门
Amen.
我想提供一个线索
I'd like to report some strange activity...
玛戈邓恩拥有的木棚附近有可疑活动
near the woodshed on the property of one Margo Dunne.
“公布怀孕？若无，打电话通报”
“杀了自己？”
你好
Hey-
邓恩先生  - 柯林斯先生
Mr. Dunne. Mr. Collings.
我认识你，我在义工中心见过你
I know you. I saw you at the volunteer center.
我想帮忙
I wanted to help.
希望你不介意我来找你
Well, I hope you don't mind me coming by.
我从你写给我太太的信上得到地址
I got your address from this letter that you wrote my wife.
爱咪和我很喜欢失传的书信艺术
Amy and I believe in the lost art of letter-writing.
我总是想，为什么发生了那些事后
I always wondered why you kept in touch after...
你们还有联络
everything.
你们在寄宿学校交往了两年对吗？
You were together for two years in boarding school, right?
她是我第一个认真的女友
She was my first serious girlfriend.
你们为什么分手？  - 这是个怪问题
Why did you break up? That's a strange question.
你对她不好吗？你劈腿吗？
Did you treat her bad? Did you cheat on her?
这个问题很无礼
That's a rude question.
我告诉你爱咪跟我说的故事
Let me tell you what Amy told me.
她甩了你，你完全无法接受
She dumped you, you completely unraveled.
你跟踪她，威胁她
You stalked her, you threatened her...
试图在她床上自杀之后被送到疗养院
and you attempted suicide in her bed and were institutionalized.
你太太失踪了，你却大老远来说这个？
Your wife is missing, and you came all this way to tell me this?
我想也许会有不同的说法
I thought there might be another side to this story.
柯林斯先生
Mr. Collings.
妈的
Fuck.
爱咪艾略特邓恩的失踪案
...the missing persons case of Amy Elliott Dunne.
“神奇的爱咪”系列童书就是以她为灵感
She is the beautiful blonde inspiration for the Amazing Amy kids' book series.
你又在看那本日记了？
You're reading that diary again?
你知道结尾是什么
You know how it ends.
我对它很有兴趣
It interests me.
隆妲
Hey, Rhonda.
“他会杀了我”，结束
"He's gonna kill me." The end.
为什么他要去他爸的家烧日记？
Why did he go to his dad's house to burn it?
那是私人住宅，而且没人
It's private. There's no one there.
为什么他没确定日记烧完了？
Why didn't he make sure it actually burned?
因为警报响了，你还拿着手电筒
Because he tripped the alarm. You were up his ass with a flashlight.
整件事感觉怪怪的
The whole thing just feels hinky.
比方说找到写着“线索”的信封
Like finding an envelope marked "Clue."
你听过这句话吗？
You ever hear the expression...
“最简单的通常是正确答案”
"The simplest answer is often the correct one"?
其实我从来不相信这句话
Actually, I've never found that to be true.
晚安  - 晚安
Good night. Good night.
你好
Hey-
“7月10日  事发之后五日”
猫王到密苏里来了
Elvis is in Missouri.
多谢老天，请进
Thank God. Come on in.
首先你需要了解，爱咪喜欢教训别人
First thing you have to understand about Amy she loves to teach lessons.
扮演上帝  - 对，旧约圣经的上帝
Play God. Yeah, Old Testament God.
好，继续说
Okay. Keep talking.
他发现我跟安蒂有外遇
She finds out I've been cheating on her with Andie...
就决定给我个教训
decides to teach me a lesson.
假装她自己死掉，让我背黑锅
Fakes her own death, frames me for it.
屋里的血迹，信用卡，寿险
Blood in the house, credit cards, life insurance.
还有她的寻宝游戏
She does the treasure hunt.
寻宝游戏是关键
Now, the treasure hunt is critical.
她带我走一遍出轨的地方，打我的脸
She's taking us on a tour of my infidelities. Rubbing my nose in it.
然后把第一条线索留给警方
And she leaves clue number one for the police...
让他们到我的办公室
which will lead them back to my office...
我跟安蒂也经常在那里…
which is a place where Andie and I would often...
然后她留下一条红内裤
And she leaves a pair of red panties.
很淫秽，看起来很糟
Right. Racy, looks bad.
线索二  - 我爸的房子
Clue two. My father's house.
这也是我有时候会跟安蒂去的地方
Another place where Andie and I would occasionally have relations.
线索三？  - 木棚
Clue three? Woodshed.
这里也是…  - 我的天
Also a location... Oh, my God.
我们的选择不多  - 宾馆啊
We had limited options. A hotel.
爱咪会看到信用卡帐单  - 用安蒂的
Amy would have seen the credit card bill.  Put it on Andie's credit card.
安蒂的帐单会寄给她爸妈
Andie's statement went right to her parents.
尼克，玛戈，我们可以去褐色小屋吗？
Ew. Nick, Margo, can we head over to the little brown house?
这条线索是到…  - 我爸的房子
This leads us to what? My dad's house.
爸的房子是蓝色的
Dad's house is blue.
爸妈离婚后，他不在我们身边
After the divorce, when Dad wasn't coming around...
我会假装他是化名“褐”先生的间谍
I used to pretend that he was a spy named Mr. Brown, who...
为了小孩的安全不得不离开他们
for the sake of his children's safety, had to deny their existence.
你没告诉过我这件事
You never told me that.
但你告诉了她？
You told her that?
你的办公室里有一条暗示的内裤
We've got incriminating red panties in your office.
你的木棚里有各种昂贵的玩意儿
We've got a Showcase Showdown worth of crap in your woodshed.
你爸的房子里到底有什么？
So, what in God's name is at your father's house, Nick?
说实话
And be honest.
我一点头绪也没有
I honestly have no idea.
“禁止进入”
不管他们找到什么，一定对你很不利
Well...Whatever they found, I think it's safe to assume that it's very bad.
现在有很多失控的情况
We got a lot of uncontained issues here.
尼克，你知道爱咪是怎么想的吗？
Nick, do you have any idea as to what Andie's mindset is?
我们从她不见那天就没再对话了
Well, we haven't communicated since the vigil.
好吧，爱咪的父母呢？
Okay. Amy's parents?
不，这样…  - 压力更大
No, it's... More pressure.
现在有个受伤的小女友随时会爆料
We got a hurt, young girlfriend... who will no doubt go public at any moment.
安蒂不会的  - 她会
No, Andie won't do that. She will.
她们一定会，我不是针对她
They always do. Don't take it personally.
爱咪让我们陷入困境
Amy's got us in an interesting bind.
我们要告诉警察安蒂的事  - 真的吗？
We need to tell the cops about Andie. Really?
安蒂会变成你杀害爱咪的另一个动机
Right now, Andie just gives you another motive.
我们要告诉警察木棚的事
We need to tell the cops about the woodshed.
我们要抢占先机
We need to be on the front end of that.
但是我得警告你接下来的事
But I'm gonna warn you as to what will happen.
他们会开始调查玛戈
They'll go after Margo.
他们不能这样吧？可以吗？
They can't do that, can they?
她是共犯，帮你藏匿证据
She's your accomplice. She helped you hide the evidence.
她很有可能知道你杀了爱咪
In all likelihood, she knows that you killed Amy.
天哪
Oh, God.
我们要怎么办？
Well, what are we going to do?
我们要找到爱咪
We find Amy.
不，其他的策略都不中要害
No. Any other strategy is missing the point.
我认识两个厉害的前秘密探员
I've got two ex-Secret Service guys that are really good.
我会交给他们
I'll put them on it.
但他们要从何开始，尼克？
But where do they start, Nick?
爱咪会去哪里？
Where would Amy go?
我完全不知道
I have no idea.
Oh!
我们有计分吗？
Are we keeping score?
干嘛啦
Hey!
我以为我们暂时不会招惹男人
I thought we were steering clear of men for a while.
他人很好
He's nice.
因为他想上你
Because he wants to fuck you.
她还在意她的前夫？
She's still moping about her ex?
他也被劈腿了
He got cheated on, too.
我们是这鸟地方最惨的三个人
We three are the saddest sacks in all the Ozarks.
我不惨
I'm not sad.
我很愤怒
I'm angry-
这就是了
There you go.
我太太离开我的时候我差点喝挂
I almost drank myself to death when my wife left me.
我差点自杀，你相信吗？
I was gonna kill myself. Can you believe that?
别让他开心
Don't give him the pleasure.
我本来要跳进墨西哥湾
I was going to drown myself in the Gulf of Mexico...
让我自己变成鲨鱼的晚餐
let myself be dinner for the great whites.
海湾里只有公牛鲨，纽奥良小姐
Gulf is bull sharks, Miss Nawlins.
为什么我要死？混蛋的又不是我
Why should I die? I'm not the asshole.
请把这句话做成T恤
Please put that on a T-shirt.
Oh!
有钱小妞，我以为你说你破产了
Miss Moneybags. l thought you said you were broke.
那可是一大笔钱呢
That's a fat wad.
都是零钞而已
It's mostly singles.
零钞？你是脱衣舞娘吗？
Singles? What are you, a stripper?
你在“沼泽女”还是“藏宝柜”？
Swamp Girls, or Treasure Chest?
我们只是开玩笑的
We're just teasing.
纽奥良人不开玩笑的吗？
Don't they tease people down in NOLA?
尼克邓恩随时会被逮捕
We can expect Nick Dunne's arrest any day now.
家里有血迹，庞大的债务，意外怀孕
We've got blood in the house, huge debt, an unwanted pregnancy.
还有爱咪艾略特邓恩失踪五天
And we have Amy Elliott Dunne, missing for five days...
必须为她主持公道
crying out for justice.
我们很快就回来
We'll be right back.
“7月11日  事发之后六日”
坦纳想跟你提一个很烂的点子
Tanner has a very bad idea he's going to pitch you.
什么？
Yeah?
明天去上莎朗薛贝尔的节目
You're doing Sharon Schieber tomorrow in St. Louis.
太危险了
It could go so wrong.
而且还要说出安蒂的事
And you are going to tell her about Andie.
不可能
Nope. Whoa, whoa, whoa.
听起来这点子糟透了
That sounds like a very bad idea.
你已经三天没有她的消息了
You haven't heard from her in three days.
她是随时会爆的炸弹，你得先自首
This is a ticking time bomb. You've gotta throw yourself on it.
大家会恨死我  - 然后会原谅你
People are gonna hate me. And then, they will forgive you.
在电视上承认自己是大混蛋的家伙？
A guy admitting that he's a gigantic asshole on television?
大家会有同理心
People empathize with that.
为什么不发表声明就算了？  - 你要露脸
Why don't we just put out a statement? They need to see you.
莎朗的特别节目有一千万的观众
Sharon's specials, they get 10 million viewers.
如果她相信你，就会为你而战
She is a crusader. If she takes you on as a cause...
她会问一些很难回答的问题
She's going to ask real questions.
我会训练你，就像作证那样
I will drill you as if you were doing a deposition.
教你怎么回话
What to say, what not to say.
让他耍猴戏？
A trained monkey?
耍猴戏可以让你逃过死刑
A trained monkey who doesn't get the lethal injection.
尼克，这个案子和大众观感有关
Nick, this case is about what people think of you.
他们一定要喜欢你
They need to like you.
上节目会让几百万的观众看到你
Now, you do this and you will reach millions of those people.
也许我只需要让一个人看到我
Maybe I only need to reach one.
谁？
Hello?
宝贝
Hey, baby.
等一下
One minute.
你好  - 你好
Hey. Hey-
你要走了？
You clearing out?
我只是在打扫
No, I'm just cleaning up.
让我们进来跟你道别啊
Let us come in and say goodbye.
我离开前会去…
I'll come by before...
我们来帮你
Let us give you a hand.
对，你得把这里清干净
Yeah, you gotta clear everything out, here.
桃乐丝可挑剔了
Dorothy is a real stickler.
就算留下个空衣架都不行
Not even a spare hanger can you leave behind.
你得确定里头没东西
Gotta make sure nothing's tucked inside.
不管是袜子
A sock...
内衣裤还是任何东西
or undies or what have you.
你很厉害啊
You did a real good job.
钱在哪里，亲爱的？
Where is the money, sweetheart?
掀开她的衣服
Look under her dress.
他说服你这么做的吗？
He talked you into this?
我说服他这么做的
I talked him into it.
你们一走我就会叫警察
The second you leave, I'm calling the cops.
你的眼镜是假的，头发染棕
Your glasses are fake. Your hair's dyed all hamster.
你说你叫南西，但叫你都不回
You say your name's Nancy, but you don't even answer to it half the time.
你在躲藏，我不知道原因也不在乎
You're hiding. I don't know why, and I don't really care.
但你不可能会叫警察
But you ain't gonna call the cops.
我根本不认为你有被打过
And I don't think you've ever really been hit before.
Ow!
我的妈啊
Holy shit.
抱歉，但我们需要这笔钱
Sorry, but we really need the money.
下次小心点吧
Next place, be more careful, okay?
外面有很多比我们坏的人
There are a lot of people out there a lot worse than we are.
抱歉，你不能睡在这里
Excuse me. You can't sleep here.
“7月12  日事发之后七日”
我没有杀我太太
I did not kill my wife.
再试一次，有感情一点
Why don't you try it again? A little less wooden.
我没有杀我太太
I didn't kill my Wife.
你干嘛？  - 每次你表现出得意
What are you doing? Every time you look smug...
或是生气或紧张，我就会用软糖丢你
or annoyed or tense, I'm gonna hit you with a gummy bear.
这样会让我比较不紧张吗？  - 再试一次
That's supposed to make me less tense? Let's try it again.
邓恩先生，听说你和妻子有点问题
Mr. Dunne, from what I understand you and your wife had some bumps.
对，我们这几年过得不好，我失业了
Yeah, we had some tough years. Um, I lost my job.
你们两个
You both did.
我们都失业了
We both lost our jobs.
我必须搬回家才能照顾母亲
I had to move back home so we could take care of my mother...
但她因癌症过世，我的父亲他…
who was dying of cancer and my dad, who had...
提到你父亲是没用的
Your dad's scorched earth.
说说你母亲吧，你们有多亲密
Let's talk about your mom, how close you were.
继续
Go on.
一段时间后我们越来越紧绷
For a while, things had been building up.
“紧绷”暗示接着有断裂，不要用这个字
"Built up" implies that an explosion is coming. No.
终于我们走上了错误的道路
At a certain point, we got on the wrong track.
我一时把持不住
I had a moment of weakness.
你的“一时”持续了15个月以上
Your "moment" was over 15 months.
我不尊重我的妻子
I disrespected my wife.
我不草重我的婚姻
And I disrespected my marriage.
我永远都会后悔
And I'll always regret it.
这样可以
That works.
不要怕扮演一个愚蠢的丈夫，尼克
Don't be afraid to play up the dufus husband thing, Nick.
“我是白痴，还是个笨蛋
"I was an idiot. I'm a fuck-up.
我没有一件事做对的”
"Everything I do is wrong."
我承认，男人就是会犯错的笨蛋
I know. What men are supposed to do in general.
谢谢  - 感觉怎么样？
- Thank you. - How do you feel?
很好，小戈，帮我拿那个盒子
I feel good. Go, can you pass me that box, please?
这是爱咪送我的33岁生日礼物
It's Amy's 33rd birthday present to me.
你讨厌那支手表
You hate that watch.
不，小戈，我爱这支表
No, Go. I love that watch.
如同我爱这条领带
Just like I love this tie.
如同我爱我妻子
Just like I love my wife.
是你
It's you!
对不起
I'm sorry.
我的老天
Good God.
上礼拜
Last week...
我说我要离开
I threatened to leave,
他说他会找到我，杀了我
and he said he'd find me and he'd kill me.
所以我消失了
So, I disappeared.
我的宝宝没了
I lost the baby.
我根本不敢跟我爸妈说
I couldn't even tell my parents.
我觉得好丢脸，好害怕
I'm so ashamed and I'm so afraid.
他在找你
Well, he is looking for you.
他三天前突然到我家来
He showed up on my doorstep three days ago.
他从我写给你的信找到我
He tracked me from my letters to you.
你都留下来了
You saved them.
知道你还在这世界上
Knowing you were out there...
我才能撑过那些年
was the only thing that's kept me going these past few years.
我们去找警察，跟他们解释一切
Let's go to the police. You can explain everything.
不行，我现在不能现身
No, I can't turn up now.
我会变成众矢之的
I'd be a pariah. Everyone would hate me.
我想让尼克进监狱错了吗？
Is it wrong to want Nick to go prison?
他应该为了他的行为入狱
He should go to prison for what he's done.
让我安排你住到我的湖边别墅
I'm setting you up at my lake house.
那里完全没有人会打扰
It's utterly secluded.
你为什么对我这么好？
Why are you so good to me?
你知道为什么
You know why.
不好意思
Excuse me.
我认识你吧？
I know you, don't I?
不认识
No.
你是诺兰家的吧？
You're one of the Nolan girls, right?
不是，我们是加拿大人，抱歉
No, we're from Winnipeg. Excuse us. Oh.
我们该走了
We should leave.
等一下
Just a second.
是邦妮警探，我再打给她
That was Boney. I'll call her later.
坦纳，很高兴见到你
Tannen Nice to see you.
莎朗，你好
Sharon! Hi.
希望这值得我的时间
Hope this is worth my while.
你一定会很高兴的
You're gonna be very happy.
我是莎朗
Sharon.
薛贝尔女士，非常谢谢你这么做
Ms. Schieber. Thank you so much for doing this.
开始前你需要什么饮料或食物吗？
Can I get you anything to drink or eat before we get started?
不了，我吃过一些软糖了
No, I had some gummy bears.
搞什么鬼？
What the fuck?
怎么了？
I'm sorry?
神奇爱咪失踪案出现意外进展
We have a major shocking development in the Amazing Amy disappearance.
请看现场报导
We go live to that story now.
我的天
Oh, my God.
你这个小荡妇
You little slut.
我叫做安蒂费兹杰罗
My name is Andie Fitzgerald.
尼可拉斯邓恩是我在…
I met Nicholas Dunne...
米尔谷学院的创意写作课老师
when he was my creative writing teacher at Mill Valley.
她为什么穿得像个保姆？
Why is she dressed like a babysitter?
我觉得非常羞愧
I am deeply ashamed...
居然和一个有妇之夫发生婚外情
of having been romantically involved with a married man.
她明明长了一对欠人射的奶子
The girl with the giant cum-on-me tits.
我本来真的相信我们相爱
I truly believed we were in love.
现在看起来像个保守派教徒
Now, she looks like a fucking Mennonite.
我知道这不是借口
I know that is no excuse.
的确不是
No, it is not.
我内心并不相信尼克邓恩会为我杀人
I do not, in my heart, believe Nick Dunne would have killed for me.
我为所有关心爱咪的人祷告
My prayers go out to everyone who loves Amy.
我为他们承受的痛苦道歉
I apologize for the pain this has caused them.
我们过去将尼克邓恩视如己出
We have loved Nick Dunne like a son.
一切到今天为止
That love ended today.
走吧，别让这些事阴魂不散
Come on, you're staring at ghosts.
他用一个又一个谎言回报我们的信任
He met our trust with lie after lie.
我们现在坚决相信
We now absolutely believe...
尼克与我们女儿的失踪有关
Nick is involved in the disappearance of our daughter.
我们的神奇爱咪
Our Amazing Amy.
真是太令人期待了
Well, this just got very exciting.
给我们一点时间
We need a moment.
我们得取消访问
We're gonna have to bow out of this.
一切都没变  - 一切都变了
Nothing has changed. Everything has changed.
一小时前我们要这么做，现在呢？
An hour ago, we were ahead of this. Now?
我可以处理  - 我们现在要防守
I can handle this. We're on the defense.
现在情况完全不一样了
This is a completely different dynamic.
我可以处理  - 她会把你生吞活剥
I can handle it.  She's going to eat you alive.
相信我
Just trust me.
好吧
Okay-
很好
Great.
给他别上麦克风
Mic him.
1，2，3，4，5
One, two, three, four, five.
谢谢
Thank you.
他不应该对化妆师笑
He shouldn't smile at the makeup artist.
真的
Yeah, no kidding.
开始拍摄，5，4
Roll tape. Five... four...
3，2
three... two...
我真不敢相信你表现得这么好
Seriously, I can't believe how fucking good you were.
爱咪会引出我最好的一面  - 够了
Amy brings out the best in me. Don't.
至少之后这24小时你们要注意点
Keep it together, you two.At least for the next 24 hours.
大家都讨厌你，女人想挖出你的眼睛
People still hate you.
安蒂很有爆点
Women want to scratch your eyes out.Andie was really good TV.
她是好人  - 这就是问题
She's a good person. Therein lies the problem.
撑过今晚
Ride this out...
明天莎朗的节目播出，就是全新的你
and when Sharon airs tomorrow,we'll be looking at a whole new you.
但是在那之前
But, until then...
不要露面
don't show your face.
没有问题
No problem.
欢迎
Welcome.
当自己家吧
Make yourself at home.
这里有音乐，卫星电视
I've got music, satellite...
随选电影
Netflix.
他本来是她的老师
He was her teacher!
串流视讯
Roku.
当然也有网路
Internet, obviously.
他应该是成年人
Here is a supposedly grown man...
如果还有什么你想要但这里没有的
If there is ever anything you have a taste for and you can't find it...
你就告诉我，我帮你带来
just let me know and I will get it for you.
他教书教到床上去了
Instead of the A-B-C's, he taught her the birds and the bees.
想想看她母亲现在会怎么想
And just think how her mother must feel at a time like this.
酒窖在楼下
Wine cellar's downstairs.
我也会帮你带些衣服来
l'll get you some clothes, too.
也不是说我不欣赏你的朴实装扮
Not that I don't appreciate Bait Shop Chic.
地板都加热了，你可以调整温度
The floors are heated, just dial to your liking.
浴袍和毛巾在这里，还有蒸汽浴
There's robes and towels. The shower has steam.
浴缸有按摩系统
The bathtub has a massage cycle.
如果你心情好可以欣赏美景
There's a great view, if you're in the mood.
心情不好就拉上遮光窗帘
Blackout curtains if you're not.
床是萨佛依的
The bed is Savoir.
你一睡就会爱上它
You'll never get a better sleep.
OH！
Oh.
这正是我需要的
Oh, this is just what I need.
我累坏了
I'm so exhausted.
那么我就不打扰你了
I'll leave you to it, then.
爱咪，我好高兴你在这里
Amy, l am so happy that you are here.
我希望你不要再担心了
And I don't want you to worry for one moment.
这里到处都有监视摄影机
There are cameras everywhere.
外面，整栋房子，还有入口都有
The exterior, all along the grounds, the entryway.
任何人
Anyone...
如果从这里进出
who is caught coming or going...
都会被录下来
will be recorded.
你在这里安全得不得了
Ah.You are more than safe.
我不会再让你离开了
And I am not letting you get away again.
“7月13日  事发之后八日”
早安  - 别吓我
Good morning! Don't do that!
对不起
I'm sorry.
我必须觉得安全
I need to feel safe.
你非常安全
You are very safe.
你在做什么？  - 没事
What have you been up to? Nothing.
爱咪，我不是尼克
Amy, I'm not Nick.
没那么简单
It's hard for me.
长年以来在别人掌控之下
After so many years under someone's thumb...
我知道那种感觉
I know just what that feels like.
我可没有掌控过你
You were never under my thumb.
我被你牵着走  - 从来没有
On your leash. Never
这是新的开始
A new start.
正常的衣服
Decent clothes.
染发剂，化妆品，小钳子
Hair dye. Makeup. Tweezers.
这里有一间俯视湖面的健身房
There's a gym overlooking the lake.
你越快恢复原貌，就越能觉得自在
The sooner you look like yourself the sooner you'll feel like yourself.
我晚上买东西来陪你看莎朗的节目
I'll get groceries for tonight we'll watch Sharon Schieber, and finally move on.
我想我自己看就可以了
I think that's something I should watch on my own.
少胡说
Nonsense.
我会回来的
I'll be back.
我很期待
And I am looking forward...
和爱咪艾略特重聚
to my reunion with Amy Elliott.
太好了
Great.
各位晚安，我是莎朗薛贝尔
Good evening, I'm Sharon Schieber.
我们今晚独家…  - 快点
Tonight, exclusively... Hurry up.
这位丈夫打破沉默，谈起妻子的失踪
A husband breaks his silence not just on his wife's disappearance...
还解释了他的出轨和那些可怕的传言
but on his infidelity, and all those shocking rumors.
尼克邓恩
Nick Dunne...
现在全美国最痛恨的人应该就是你
you're probably the most hated man in America right now.
我可能是，我也罪有应得
I probably am. And I probably deserve it.
那条领带是我买的
I bought that tie.
你杀了你妻子吗，尼克？
Did you kill your Wife, Nick?
我没有杀我妻子
I did not kill my wife.
我不是杀人犯
I am not a murderer.
但是你出轨
But you were unfaithful.
我曾经出轨
I was unfaithful.
我为此感到羞愧
And I am deeply ashamed.
除此之外，你还让爱咪的父母
And, on top of that, you allowed Amy's parents...
你的朋友，家乡所有的乡亲
her friends, all the people in your hometown...
相信你是想找到失踪妻子的深情丈夫
believe you were a loving husband, desperate to find his missing wife.
我真的很想找到我失踪的妻子
Well, I am desperate to find my missing wife.
尽管你这么说，但我们怎么能相信你
You say that, but I'm wondering how you expect us to believe you...
毕竟我们已经知道你说了谎
now that we know you're a liar.
我没有坦诚我的外遇
I didn't come forward with my affair...
因为这会让我看起来非常糟糕
because I knew it would make me look really, really bad.
但是我已经不在乎了
But I don't care about that anymore.
我只想找到我的妻子
I just want to find my wife.
我只是想弄清楚  - 我说得清楚一点
I'm just trying to get clear... Let me be clear.
就算我没杀人也不表示我是好人
Just because l am not a murderer doesn't make me a good guy.
我不是好人
I'm not a good guy.
对于我完美的妻子，我是糟糕的丈夫
I was a bad husband to a great wife.
我打破了对她许下的承诺
I broke the vow that I made to her.
那些都是好听话，尼克
Those are pretty words, Nick.
说这些有什么意义？
But what does that really mean to you?
基本上代表我只会出一张嘴
It basically means that I was a con artist.
我七年前认识爱咪艾略特
I met Amy Elliott seven years ago.
我完全被她迷住了
I was completely transfixed.
爱咪就是有这种能力
Amy can do that to you.
我只是个来自普通人家的普通人
I was this average guy from an average place...
胸无大志
with mediocre aspirations.
但我认识了这个令我感到神奇的女人
And I met a woman who dazzled me.
我想让她爱上我
And I wanted her to love me...
所以我假装自己很优秀
so I pretended to be better than I was.
当我们结婚时，我承诺我会那么优秀
When we got married, I promised to be that guy.
那个人会努力工作
That guy who works harder.
在生活中，在行动上…
That guy who, who lives and acts...
在爱情里都像她一样热情
and loves with as much passion as she does.
但我让她失望了
But I failed her.
我没有选择正确的路
Instead of doing what was right...
而是选择了简单的路
I did what was easy.
你听起来有自信能补偿妻子
You talk like a man who believes he can make amends to his wife.
而且相信妻子还活着
Who believes his wife is still alive.
她还活着
She is still alive.
你可以看着镜头吗？
Will you look at that camera for me?
请你看着镜头
Will you look in the lens...
对你妻子说话
and talk to your wife?
如果她还活着，今晚能看到你说话
If she is out there, able to hear and see you tonight...
你想对她说什么，尼克？
what would you like to say to her, Nick?
爱咪，我爱你
Amy, I love you.
你是我认识最好的人
You're the best person I've ever known.
我已经为我的作为付出代价
And I've taken myself to the woodshed for the way that I've treated you.
如果你回来，我保证
And if you come back, I promise...
我会用我的每一天补偿你
I will spend every day making it up to you.
我会成为我承诺做到的男子汉
I will be the man that I promised you I would be.
我爱你
I love you.
回家吧
Come home.
给我
Here.
不管你怎么想
Regardless of what you thought...
大家怎么说？
What does it say?
我想我们都同意
...I think we can all agree...
我的天，你表现得完美极了
Oh, my God. You fucking killed it.
你跟以前完全不一样
...there's more to him than meets the eye.
他们为你疯狂
They're going crazy for you.
他们讨厌我，他们喜欢我，他们恨我
They disliked me, they liked me, they hated me.
现在他们爱我
And now they love me.
一个真诚，诚实，值得尊重的人
...a candor and an honesty that's worthy of respect.
他确实赢得我的尊重
He's certainly earned mine.
怎么了？
What is it?
我是莎朗薛贝尔，各位晚安
I'm Sharon Schieber. Good night.
玛戈邓恩，这是你家的搜索票
Margo Dunne, this is a search warrant for your property.
我通常不理会线报
I usually ignore tipline calls...
但邻居担心你家木棚有可疑人士出没
but a neighbor was concerned about a strange man around your woodshed.
打电话给坦纳
Call Tanner.
好，妈的
Okay. Fuck!
你女朋友很可爱啊，尼克
Girlfriend's real cute, Nick.
是为了这事吗？
Is that what this is about?
我在调查过程中已经对你非常宽容了
I have treated you more than fair throughout this entire investigation.
我也一再给你机会洗清嫌疑
I gave you the benefit of the doubt over and over.
每次你说出蠢话
Every time you said something stupid...
我都想“他可能只是蠢”
I thought, "Maybe he's just stupid."
但我错了，就是这么回事
But I was wrong. That's what this is about.
这些是你打高尔夫用的吗？
Are these the clubs you don't play golf with?
这都不是我的
None of that is mine.
这些都不是我放的
None of this was put here by me.
这些球杆很高级，这边是个男人窝啊
Those are nice clubs. You got the makings of a real man cave.
等太太消失后就可以用来享乐了
Everything just waiting until the wife goes away for good.
尼克
Nick!
你们不能这样  - 当然可以
Hey, you can't do that! Of course we can.
爱咪，是时候忘掉过去了
Amy, it's time to move on.
我可以怎么帮你？
What can I do to help?
我需要一点时间思考
I need some time to think.
你不需要  - 戴西
That's the last thing you need.  Desi...
你已经让我抱着希望20年
Twenty years, you have kept me dangling.
终于你在昨晚来找我，你选了我
Finally, last night, you came to me, and you chose me.
跟着你的直觉吧
Follow that instinct.
不要相信让你变成这样的直觉
Don't trust the instinct that left you beaten and homeless...
害你住在车里，担心性命安危
sleeping in your car, fearing for your life.
我不会霸王硬上弓
I'm not gonna force myself on you.
我了解你的意思，戴西
I understand what you're saying, Desi.
我真的懂
I do.
我一直没受到应有的对待
I've been so mistreated for so long.
我已经忘记怎么做了
I've forgotten how to behave.
我明天会搬来
I'll move in here tomorrow...
我们可以一起想办法
and we'll work it out together.
我只想让你做回你自己
I just want you to be you again.
他们带走玛戈就是要搞你
They only took Margo to fuck with you.
她不能在那里多待他妈的一秒
She's not spending another fucking second in there.
我要进去告诉他们一切
I'm gonna go in, and I'm gonna tell them everything.
什么？
What?
我们不能对邦妮说什么
We tell Boney very little.
没有尸体，没有凶器
Without a body, without a murder weapon...
除非你自首，他们不能定你罪
their only hope is a confession.
所以让他们说话就好
So, you let them do all the talking.
这样你的辩护才会有力
That way, we can jump-start your defense.
我的辩护就是真相
The truth is my defense.
你认得这些东西吗？
Recognize these?
认得，是爱咪给我的周年礼物
Yes. It's Amy's anniversary present to me.
她是这样告诉你她怀孕的吗？
Was that how she told you she was pregnant, Nick?
爸爸，妈妈，宝宝，然后你抓狂了？
Mommy, Daddy, baby, and that made you real mad?
没有
No.
认得这个吗？  - 从来没看过这东西
Recognize this? Never seen that before in my life.
爱咪的日记，在你父亲房子里找到的
It's Amy's diary. We found this at your father's house.
这是你妻子的笔迹吗？
Is this your wife's handwriting?
他不是笔迹专家  - 看起来是
He's not a handwriting ex... Looks like it.
我们的专家也这么想
Our experts thought so, too.
你想玩是非题游戏吗？
Do you wanna play a little true or false?
好啊
Sure.
“他把糖粉从我嘴上拨开，才能亲吻我”
"And then he brushes the sugar off my lips so he can taste me."
是真的
Yeah, that's true.
你以为“奎宁”是一种鱼？
You thought quinoa was a fish?
这也是真的
That is also true, yes.
她说她想怀孕，你就攻击她
She wanted to get pregnant, you assaulted her.
我打她？从来没有
I hit her? No, never happened.
“推”，上面说“推”  - 绝对没有
"Pushed," it says "pushed." Absolutely not.
我从来没碰过她
I never touched her.
她打算买一把枪
She tried to buy a gun.
我怀疑，但我不知道
I doubt that, but I don't know.
我可以念最后一篇吗？
Shall I read the last entry?
当然
Sure.
“这个男人可能会杀了我”
"This man may kill me."
她自己这么写“这个男人可能会杀了我”
In her own words, "This man may kill me."
当作收尾真好用
It's kind of a convenient end note.
下次记得
For future reference...
事实上你并不是笔迹专家
the truth, you are not a handwriting expert.
我知道了
Okay, I know.
茱迪的把手
Judy's missing handle.
大约5乘10公分的棍子
Big as a two-by-four, right? Big as a club.
我们第一天就在你家书房的壁炉发现
We found this day one, in the fireplace in your home office.
本来不知道那是什么，但七月生火？
We didn't know what the hell it was, but fire in July?
我们收起来做为证据
We bagged it.
我也从来没看过这个
I've never seen that before either.
我们测试过了，火不能消除血迹
We just tested it. Fire doesn't erase blood, Nick.
所以，尼可拉斯邓恩
So, finally, Nicholas Dunne...
你因为谋杀妻子遭到逮捕
you're under arrest for the murder of your wife.
不要再说话了
Do not say another word.
我的说法呢？  - 尼克
What about my side? Nick!
“7月26日  事后之后二十一日”
还要咖啡吗？
More coffee?
好啊
I'd love it.
记得我们跷课开车去鳕鱼角那次吗？
Remember that time we skipped school and drove to the Cape?
天哪，我记得，现捞的龙虾
Oh, God, yeah. Lobster right from the ocean.
这里让我想起当时
This reminds me of that.
永不结束的假期
Never-ending holiday.
你不无聊吗？
You're not bored?
戴西，我怎么会无聊？
Desi, how could I be bored?
我们可以讨论18世纪的交响乐
You can discuss 18th-century symphonies...
19世纪印象派，用法文引用普鲁斯特
19th-century Impressionists, quote Proust in French.
尼克对文化的定义是实境秀马拉松
Nick's idea of culture was a reality TV marathon...
而且一只手还放在四角裤里
with one hand down his boxers.
我得走了
I really have to get going.
但我会尽快回来
But I will be back just as soon as I can.
我的钥匙
My keys.
谢谢你
Thank you.
Ow!
年轻人都这样穿
That's how the kids wear it.
邓恩，你的律师来了
Dunne? You got one hell of a lawyer.
你来了
Hey-
你还好吗？  - 很好，你呢？
Are you okay?  Yes. Are you?
还好
Yeah.
我们走吧
Let's go.
什么意思？
What does this mean?
我们保你出来了
Well, you're out on bond.
你可以在家休息，准备受审
You can relax at home while we prep for trial.
头低下来
Keep your head down.
坦纳，有没有任何爱咪的消息？
Tanner, is there any fucking lead on Amy?
我有两个专家在查
I've got two of my best guys on it.
她凭空消失了
She's air.
回家吧，爱咪，你有种回家来
Come home, Amy. I dare you.
“8月3日  事发之后二十九日”
柯林斯先生回来了
Mr. Collings is home.
柯林斯先生你好
Hello, Mr. Collings.
我好想你
I've missed you.
我一直在想
I've been thinking...
我不想失去你
I don't wanna be without you. Oh.
留下来陪我
Stay with me.
等一切平静，我们就像你说的去希腊
And when all this dies down, we'll go to Greece, like you said.
吃章鱼，玩拼字游戏？
Octopus and Scrabble?
你觉得事情还要多久解决？
How long do you think until it's done?
不久，六个月很快就会判刑
Not long. Six months for the trial. Sentencing will be quick.
他会上诉的
He'll appeal.
我可以在国外看
I can watch the rest overseas.
慢慢来
Go slowly.
但我想要
But I want it.
别急
Don't rush.
来吧
Just do it.
用力一点
Harder.
“8月4日  事发之后三十日”
你他妈的贱女人
You fucking bitch.
别担心，你会有很多小孩的
Don't you worry, you're gonna have lots of babies.
她的伤口符合强暴特征，还有精液
Her wounds are consistent with rape. There was semen present.
我们会和戴西比对
We'll make sure it's a match.
一定会符合的
Yeah, it'll match.
非常谢谢你
Thank you very much.
你怎么想？
What do you think?
我们又是朋友了？
Are we pals again?
对，因为我知道你没有杀你老婆
Now that I know you didn't murder your wife, yes.
你怎么想？
What do you think?
绑架？这故事太疯狂了
Kidnapping? The story's insane.
她吃了很多止痛药
She's on fairly heavy painkillers.
没关系，我想帮忙
It's okay. I want to help.
邓恩太太，我知道你经历了什么
Ms. Dunne, I know what you've been through...
我们会尽快结束
so we'll keep this very brief.
可以从头到尾说明一次吗？
Can you walk us through what happened?
那天早上门铃响了
That morning, the doorbell rang.
一切都很正常
So normal.
我打开门
I opened the door.
很奇怪
So strange.
从高中开始他就纠缠我不放
Since high school, he won't ever go away.
我只是不想跟他撕破脸
And I've just tried to be nice to him.
我会回信给他
Answer his letters.
安抚他
Keep him calm.
我的天哪
Oh, my God.
是我鼓励他的
Oh, I've encouraged him.
你不能怪自己
You can't blame yourself.
他硬闯进来
He pushed inside.
抓住我
And he grabbed me.
但我逃跑了，躲到厨房
But I got away, and ran to the kitchen.
结果他拿东西打我
And he clubbed me.
我就昏过去了
I collapsed.
就是木偶潘趣和茱迪的棍子
That club was actually the handle to a Punch and Judy puppet.
对
Right.
寻宝游戏
Treasure hunt.
我本来把木偶藏在小戈家
I'd hidden some puppets at Go's...
戴西怎么会有那支木棍？
Then how did Desi have that handle?
我先发现的
I'd just found it.
一定是掉下来了
It must have fallen off.
I...
戴西进来时我正拿着木棍，他抢走的
was holding it when Desi pushed in. So, he got it from me.
那个木棚…
About that woodshed...
他带我去他的湖边别墅
He took me to his lake house.
把我绑在他的床上
Tied me to his bed.
跳到木棚那边，很快
Back to the woodshed real quick. Real quick.
你去藏木偶的时候
When you went to place the puppets there...
你有没有注意到
did you notice that it was packed...
那边有很多东西？
Lots of stuff.
就和你丈夫信用卡购买的清单一样
Corresponding to purchases made on credit cards in your husband's name.
尼克会乱刷卡
Nick and credit cards.
他买东西我会唠叨，可能是这样吧
He buys, I nag. I don't know, probably.
他藏很多东西在小戈家，他们很亲
He hid a lot of stuff at Go's. They're very close.
现在我可以回去解释自己如何被关在…
Now, may I go back to where I was being held prisoner...
有精神病史的男人那里了吗？
by a man with a history of mental problems?
请继续，邓恩女士
Please continue, Ms. Dunne.
戴西当晚就侵犯我
Desi assaulted me that night.
每天晚上都会
Every night.
他把我像狗一样绑住
He tied me up like a dog.
然后他会惩罚我
And then, he'd punish me.
让我挨饿
Starve me.
要我剃毛
Shave me.
性虐待我
Sodomize me.
那里到处都有摄影机
There were cameras everywhere.
拜托你们去找，找到那些影带
Please find this. Please find the tapes.
她用刀片划破他的喉咙
She slit his throat with a box cutter.
如果她一直被绑住
How did she manage to get a hold of a box cutter...
怎么能拿到刀片？
if he had her tied up the whole time?
你太太安全回家你就不能开心一点吗？
Can't you just be happy your wife is home and safe?
爱咪，我们找到你的日记了
Amy, we found your diary.
里面有很多身心受虐的严重指控
It contains many concerning allegations of mental and physical abuse.
那就是丑陋的真相
Well, it's the ugly truth.
尼克不想要宝宝
Nick didn't want a baby.
他脾气不好，我们经济拮锯
He has a temper. We had money problems.
但我爱他
But I love him.
为什么你想买枪？
Then why did you try to buy a gun?
对不起，我觉得无法集中精神
I'm sorry, I feel myself fading.
我只想弄清楚一件事
If I could just clarify one thing...
如果让你这样无能的人来办这个案子
If this case had been left in your deeply incompetent hands...
我丈夫八成等着上死刑台
my husband would be on death row...
而我也还被人五花大绑
and I'd be tied, still, spread-eagle...
邓恩女士，你很勇敢，我们问完了
Ms. Dunne, you've been very brave. We're finished.
现在我要问你
Now, I have to ask you...
你觉得和丈夫回家是安全的吗？
do you feel safe going home with your husband?
我们向上帝祷告，上帝回应了我们
We prayed to God, and God has answered our prayers.
爱咪邓恩回家了
Amy Dunne is home.
我知道各位有很多问题与疑惑
Now, I know there are a lot of questions and concerns...
但我们暂时耐住性子
but for right now, we wanna sit tight...
对密西西比河的奇迹报以感激之心
and just be thankful and grateful for this miracle on the Mississippi.
借过，各位借过
Excuse me. Excuse us, folks.
我们爱你，爱咪
We love you, Amy!
好了，你不用再装了
All right, you can stop pretending now.
我没有装
I'm not pretending.
你太完美了
You were perfect.
电视上的那个尼克才是我爱的
The Nick I saw on TV, that's the Nick I fell in love with.
你知道我只是说你想听的话，对吧？
You do know I was just telling you what you wanted to hear, right?
你就是这么了解我
That's how well you know me.
我就像是你的分身
You know me in your marrow.
好吧
Okay-
你得告诉我到底发生了什么事
You need to tell me exactly what happened.
衣服脱掉
Take off your clothes.
我要确定你没有录音
I need to make sure you're not wearing a wire.
你杀了人，爱咪，你是杀人凶手
You killed someone, Amy. You're a murderer.
我是斗士
I'm a fighter.
我为了回到你身边而战斗
I fought my way back to you.
你杀了一个人
You killed a guy.
你用刀片划开他的喉咙
You slashed his throat with a box cutter.
你上全国电视，求我救你一命
You went on national television and begged for me to save your life.
我照做了
And I obliged.
但我要那个尼克
But I want that Nick.
我要离开你
I'm leaving.
你真的觉得这样做好吗？
You really think that's smart?
洗发精
Shampoo.
被强暴的妻子负伤辛苦回到丈夫身边
Wounded, raped wife battles her way back to her husband...
结果他遗弃了她
and he deserts her.
他们会毁了你
They'll destroy you.
邻居会孤立你
Neighbors will shun you.
我会让所有人记得你对我造成的痛苦
And I'll make sure that no one forgets the pain you caused me.
我不想跟你的那些粉丝扯上任何关系
I don't want anything to do with your groupies outside.
等他们不再注意你
Once they go...
我就会离开
I go.
想一想，睡一觉再说
Give it the night. Sleep on it.
你真的有怀孕吗？
Was there ever a baby?
我可以
There can be.
晚安
Good night.
“8月5日  归来之后一日”
尼克，你好
Hey, Nick!
帅哥，你好
Hello, handsome.
要吃可丽饼吗？
Crepe?
当然
Sure.
她是他的梦中情人
She was his dream girl.
但这个被宠坏的公子哥儿得不到她
And when this spoiled, rich, entitled little boy couldn't have her...
所以绑架了她
he took her.
你们一定很引以为傲
You must be so proud.
已经四个小时了
It's been four hours.
尼克，你接下来和爱咪有什么打算？
Nick? Nick? What's next for you and Amy?
现在我们只想专注于我们的婚姻
Right now, it's all about our marriage.
当两个人相爱，却无法幸福
When two people love each other and can't make that work...
才是真正的悲剧
that's the real tragedy.
亲我的脸颊
Kiss my cheek.
我不相信那个蜘蛛女居然是美国甜心
I can't believe that fucking spider is America's sweetheart.
（8月9日  归来之后五日）
She told me she killed Desi.
她告诉我她杀了戴西
不是出于自卫，是杀人
Not self-defense. Murder.
我们可以录音吗？  - 不可能
- Can't we get a wire? - That's not gonna work.
她告诉过你一次
She told you once before.
对，但她要我全裸而且边林浴边说
Yeah, because she had me strip naked, and stand in the shower.
我发誓你们是我认识最变态的一对
I swear, you two are the most fucked-up people I've ever known.
而且我还是这方面的专家
And I specialize in fucked-up.
你和爱咪还住在一起吗？
You and Amy under the same roof?
你应该提议做个实境秀
You should pitch that as reality television.
爱咪邓恩与密西西比河的奇迹
Amy Dunne, and the Miracle on the Mississippi.
尼克和我已经受了很多折磨
Nick and I have been through some bad patches.
我们曾经在谷底
We've had our dark days.
但我们很感谢你们
But we thank you so much...
支持我们再度开始新生活，原谅尼克
for supporting us in our new life together, for forgiving Nick.
真的，你们的鼓励是最重要的
Really, your encouragement means the world.
她很厉害
Oh, she's good.
神奇的爱咪与卑微的丈夫
Amazing Amy and the Humbled Husband.
布兰森主妇实境秀
The Real Housewives of Branson.
你会好好照顾这家伙吧？
Take care of this guy, will you?
我不敢相信你就这样走了
I can't believe you're just leaving now.
你现在已经没有危险了
You are not at risk anymore.
我的处境百分百“危险”
I'm the definition of "at risk."
你有一本书约，电影改编版权
You got a book deal, a Lifetime movie, you franchised The Bar.
还有酒吧
你可能得感谢她
You may wanna thank her.
不要惹火她就是了
Just don't piss her off.
再见了，各位
See you, guys-
猫王要离开密苏里了
Elvis has left Missouri.
她一定犯了什么错
She had to have made a mistake.
我们要仔细检查爱咪的说法
We need to check Amy's story, piece by piece.
尼克，我不能帮忙
Nick, I can't do anything.
现在全国都盯着我们
We had the national spotlight on us, we stained the rug.
我们出过一次错
The case is with the Feds now, they're done.
现在联邦调查局接手了，他们结案了
但你不一定要收手
That doesn't mean you have to be done.
我必须收手
It does.
（9月9日  归来之后五周）
你在做什么？
What are you doing?
我睡不着
Couldn't sleep.
过来
Come on...
让我哄哄你
let me tuck you back in.
你知道你可以跟我睡吧？
You know you can sleep with me, right?
对，但是…
Yeah, it's just...
我还需要时间
I need more time.
我绝对不会伤害你的
I would never, ever hurt you.
但我需要你跟我合作
I do need you to participate, though.
你要做好你自己
I need you to do your part.
好
Okay.
（9月23日  归来之后七周）
Everything you have heard about my wife...
我太太说的每一字每一句
都是谎言
is a lie.
她是工于心计、心理变态的杀人犯
She is a calculating, murderous psychopath.
而我是共犯…
And I have been complicit...
尼克
Nick!
尼克，早餐好了
Nick? Breakfast.
亲爱的？
Honey?
我们应该牵手
We should hold hands.
不是一直，偶尔牵一下
Not the entire time, but on and off throughout.
“尼克，你太太回来让你感觉如何？”
"So, Nick, how does it feel to have your wife back?"
“超棒的”
"lt's fantastic.
“有多少人这么幸运
"How many people are lucky enough...
有第二次爱的机会”
"to get a second chance at love?"
“太棒了”有点浮夸
"Fantastic" is a little flippant.
“很神奇”？
"Amazing"?
你必须承认你拿了信用卡
I need you to admit that you got the credit cards...
把东西藏在小戈那里，而且推了我
and that you hid all that stuff at Go's and that you pushed me.
你承认这三件事我才觉得安全
I'm gonna need those three things to feel safe.
你得负起责任，尼克
You have to own this, Nick.
别担心，我知道该怎么说
Don't worry.I know exactly what to say.
尼克
Nick.
你家真漂亮
What a beautiful home.
我很感谢你这次接受我们访问
I so appreciate you giving us this time, Nick.
你在全国电视上
You went on national television...
告诉大家我杀了我太太
and told people that I murdered my wife.
我只是跟着故事走
I go where the story goes.
你暗示我和我妹妹乱伦
You implied that I had carnal relations with my sister.
我没有说，我只说你们“非常亲密”
I didn't use the "I" word. I said you two were "extremely close."
你和你们那票人说我毫无良知
You and a panel of nitwits diagnosed me as a sociopath.
我有小礼物
Ice-breaker.
和你的机器狗配对
To go with your robot dog.
我去找爱咪
I'll go find Amy.
她在楼下
She's downstairs.
那是什么？  - 是给你的
What is it? It's for you.
打开看看
Open it.
我不需要你再给我礼物了
I don't need any more gifts from you.
打开
Open it.
（验孕棒）
我没碰你
I didn't touch you.
你不需要
You didn't need to.
狗屁，他们通知样本销毁了
Bullshit. That notice of disposal.
你扔了之后，我捡起来的
I have that. You threw it out.
没错，就是那张通知
The notice, yes.
我要验血
I want a blood test.
我要做亲子监定
I want a paternity test.
我最爱测试了
I love tests.
你大可如你所愿地教大家恨我
You can teach those people to hate me all you want.
我不在乎了，我要离开你
I don't care. I am leaving you.
我不用教你的孩子恨你
I won't have to teach your child to hate you.
他自己就会做
He'll do that all by himself.
你他妈的贱女人
You fucking cunt!
我就是跟你结婚的贱女人
I'm the cunt you married.
你唯一喜欢自己的时候
The only time you liked yourself...
就是做到这个贱女人满意的时候
was when you were trying to be someone this cunt might like.
我不会半途而废，我是个贱女人
I'm not a quitter. I'm that cunt.
我为了你杀了我自己耶
I've killed for you. Who else can say that?
这样还不够吗？
你以为跟乡下好女孩在一起会快乐吗？
You think you would be happy with a nice Midwestern girl?
不可能，宝贝，你要的是我
No way, baby. I'm it.
看看你，你疯了，彻底地疯了
Look, you're delusional. You're insane.
为什么你想要这样？
Why would you even want this?
对，我爱过你
Yes, I loved you.
但后来我们互相僧恨，试图控制对方
And then all we did was resent each other, and try to control each other.
为彼此带来痛苦
And cause each other pain.
这就是婚姻
That's marriage.
现在我要去准备了
Now, I'm getting ready.
我再也无法眼睁睁看你们扮假面夫妻
I can't watch you play house with that thing for the next 18 years.
我不能一走了之
I can't just walk away.
你可以争取监护权
You could get custody.
我赢不了，你知道的
No, I won't. And you know it.
那是我的小孩，我不能丢下他
It's gonna be my child. I'm not gonna leave it.
你想留下来
You wanna stay.
我有责任，已经不是我想怎样就好了
I have a responsibility.It's not about what I want anymore.
你想留在她身边
You wanna stay with her.
你伤透了我的心
You're breaking my heart.
小戈，你是我的理性
Go, you're my voice of reason.
我需要你在我这边
I need you with me on this.
我当然在你那边
Of course I'm with you.
还没出生我就在你旁边了
I was with you before we were even born.
我们经历了黑暗
We've been through the darkness.
我们走出黑暗，和好
We've come out, united.
我们沟通
We communicate.
我们现在对彼此很坦诚
We're honest with each other.
是吧？
Right?
我们曾经是共犯
We're partners in crime.
然后呢？
And?
然后？
我们要当爸妈了
We're gonna be parents.
我的天哪
Oh, my goodness!
真令人开心  - 谢谢
Oh, how exciting! Thank you.
你在想什么？
"What are you thinking?"
你感觉怎么样？
"How are you feeling?"
我们对彼此做了什么？
"What have we done to each other?"
我们接下来该怎么办？
"What Will We do?"
翻译：钟沛君